In this lesson, we're going to get into the mid of
developing differentially private algorithms.
The main strategy that we're going to take to protect
individual's privacy is one of noise,
meaning we're going to add random noise to the database
and to the queries in the database in order to protect people's privacy.
Now, there are two different kinds of differential privacy, which
refer to the two different places that you can add noise.
Local differential privacy adds noise to each individual data point.
You can think of this as adding noise directly to the database or
even having individuals add noise to their own data,
before even putting it into the database.
In this setting, users are most protected as they
do not have to trust the database owner to use their data responsibly.
The other kind of differential privacy is called global differential privacy,
which adds noise to the output of the query on the database.
This means that the database itself contains all of the private information and that it's
only the interface to the data which
adds the noise necessary to protect each individual's privacy.
So what is the real difference between local and global differential privacy?
Well, if the database operator is trustworthy,
the only difference is that global differential privacy leads to
more accurate results with the same level of privacy protection.
However, this requires database owner to be trustworthy.
Namely, that the database owner should add noise properly.
In differential privacy literature,
the database owner is called a trusted curator.