Let's jump into local differential privacy.
Local differential privacy is where given a collection of individuals,
each individual adds noise to their data
before sending it to the statistical database itself.
So everything that gets thrown into the database is already noised.
So the protection is happening at a local level.
So now the question is, how much noise should we add?
Well, this varies as we'll see.
Let's start by remembering what we learned about sensitivity in database queries.
First off, we saw in previous lessons the basic sum query is not differentially private.
In truth, differential privacy always requires a form of
randomness or noise added to the query to protect from things like a differencing attack.
To discuss this, we're going to discuss something called randomized response.
Randomized response is this really amazing technique
that is used in the social sciences when
trying to learn about the high-level trends for some taboo behavior.
So if you imagine that you are perhaps a sociologist and you want to be able to
study how many people in a city have committed a certain crime,
perhaps you're going to study jaywalking.
So you sat down with 1,000 people and you wanted to ask each individual one hey,
trust me, I'm not going to tell anyone on you.
Have you ever jaywalked,
perhaps in the last week?
Well, there's this trouble that people are going to be reluctant to divulge
this information because it's technically a crime in many locations.
So the sociologist is worried that the results are going to be
skewed because some subset of population is going to answer dishonestly.
So there's this amazing technique where in a certain degree of randomness can be added to
the process such that each individual is
protected with what's called plausible deniability.
It works like this. It's really is pretty cool.
So instead of directly asking each person the question,
the first thing that a sociologist will do is present the question and then say,
"I need for you to flip a coin two times
without me seeing it and if the first coin flip is a heads,
I want you to answer my yes or no question honestly.
Did you jaywalk? But if the first coin flip is a tails,
then I want you to answer this question according to the second coin flip."
So the idea here is that half the time,
individuals are going to be answering honestly.
The other half the time,
they're going to answer randomly with a 50-50 chance of saying yes or no.
The interesting thing here is that if a person says, "Yes,
I have jaywalked in the last week," that person has a certain degree of
plausible deniability that they're only answering it because of the coin flip.
So they have this natural level of protection,
this localized differential privacy.
They have this randomness applied to
their specific data point that is local to them and that's what in theory is
able to give them the protection that gives them the freedom to answer
honestly and to provide more accurate statistics at the end of the day.
Perhaps the most extraordinary thing is that over the aggregate,
over the entire population,
the individual performing the study can then
remove this random noise because as you can imagine,
this process is that it takes the true statistic and averages it with a 50-50 coin flip.
So in this particular case,
let's say that 70 percent of people actually jaywalk, like in the real world.
Then we know that when we perform our survey,
60 percent of our results will answer yes. Let's take this slowly.
So since 70 percent of people actually jaywalk,
this means that roughly half our participants will say yes or no with
a 50 percent probability and the other will say yes or no with a 70 percent probability.
Thus when we average these two together,
the results of our survey will be 60 percent. This is incredible.
This means that we can take the result of our noise statistic
and back into the true distribution, the true result.
We can say since 60 percent of people reported that they jaywalk,
then we know that the true answer is actually centered around 70 percent and we can do
all of this without actually knowing whether any individual person jaywalks.
Pretty incredible. So now one thing we have to
acknowledge here is that the added privacy comes at the cost of accuracy.
Even though that we will on average still get the right statistics,
we're still averaging our initial result,
60 percent with random noise.
So if people happen to flip coins in a really unlikely way,
we might accidentally think that 95 percent of people are jaywalking.
It's only "in expectation" aka when we have an infinite number of samples,
an infinite number of participants,
that this noise disappears and we get the exact true distribution.
Thus we have gained privacy but we've lost some accuracy,
especially if we're only sampling over a small number of people.
This trend is true throughout the entire field of differential privacy.
Research in differential privacy can thus be grouped into two main themes.
The main goal of DP is to get
the most accurate query results with the greatest amount of privacy,
aka how can we minimize the amount of noise that we are adding,
while maximizing the amount of privacy?
The second goal is derivative of this,
which looks at who trusts or doesn't trust each other in a real world situation.
Because if you add noise to protect two people who do trust each other,
that noise was wasted and your query was less accurate than necessary.
But if you forget to add noise between two people who don't trust each other,
meaning a database curator and an individual,
then you put one of them more at risk.
So we want to minimize a noise accuracy tradeoff.
One of the strategies there is to create flexible differential privacy strategies
which fit with how people actually do and don't trust each other in the real world.
But enough on that. Let's implement local differential privacy for ourselves.