In this project, what I'd like for you to do is to
implement randomized response in our database.
You're going to "flip coins" by just using
a simple 1/0 random number generator in Python.
So for each entry in the database,
you want to flip two coins.
Generate two random 1/0 responses.
If the first coin is heads,
leave the entry in the database as it is.
If the first coin is tails,
then reset that entry in the database according to the second coin flipped as you were.
Then, I want you to perform a query both on
the original database and on the database which then modified with random bits.
Perform the mean query on both of these databases.
Return the results of both queries so that we can compare them.
After implementing this logic, however,
I want you to study how much the noise changes on
the output of the query databases of varying sizes.
Report both the true query and the noised query for databases of sizes 10,
100, 1000, and 10,000.