In this project, we're going to implement
simple local differential privacy using randomized response from scratch in Python.
Specifically, we're actually going to implement in Python,
the coin flipping example that we just talked about.
So as you may remember,
if you have a group people that you're wishing to survey about a very taboo behavior,
then we are given these interesting instructions as to how they should answer.
So they flip a coin two times and if the first coin flip was heads,
they should answer honestly.
However, if he first coin flip was tails,
they should answer according to a second coin flip.
What this does, is this gives each person plausible deniability while simply
averaging across all of their answers with a 50 percent probability of saying yes or no.
Thus, if we sample across a 1000 people,
we would carry this over 1000 people.
We interrogate a 1000 people with this question,
and around 60 percent of them answer, yes.
Then we know that the true distribution is 70 percent because 70 percent,
the true distribution has been averaged with
50 percent to get the the output of our statistical survey.
So we want to implement these steps in Python from scratch.
The way that we're going to do this is like so.
So the query function we're going to use is a mean function.
So we're going to be taking an average.
So let's say we have a database of size 10, or let's just say it's 100.
So we've got a big old database of a hundred people.
Then the true result is the mean of the database. Here we go.
Since we generate our database randomly,
with 50 percent probability of being one or zero,
the mean tends to be around 0.5.
However, we want to noise our dataset using local differential privacy.
Local differential privacy is all about adding noise to the data itself.
So in our case,
adding noise to the data means replacing some of these values with random values.
So if you remember, from this randomized response,
like sometimes they answer honestly,
so these would be the honest results in our example.
Sometimes, they answer according to a coin flip, they answer randomly.
So the first thing we need to do is actually flip two coins a 100 times.
So we'll do first coin flip equals torch.rand,
length of the database, greater than 0.5.
We'll go ahead and cast this to a float as well.
So now, we have our first coin flip for every single value in this database tensor.
So this is the coin flip for this value,
this is the coin flip for this value,
and so on and so forth.
So now, let's do this and create a second coin flip.
So now, this first coin flip is going to determine
whether we want to use the value it's actually going to database,
or whether we want to use the value that was
randomly generated according to this second coin flipper.
We can do this to create our noisy database or synthetic database or augmented database.
We'll call it augmented in the following way.
So half the time,
so if the coin flip is one,
then we want to use the database.
So it was a heads answer honestly.
So we'll call one heads.
The nice thing here is, we can do this by simply just
multiplying first coin flip by database,
because this acts as a mask.
Right. So the multiplying it times a one,
will leave in wherever the database is and multiplying it times
a zero will zero out any values in the database.
So this will return database times first coin flip,
returns a one only for
the places in the database where there actually was a one originally.
Go cast this to a float again.
So here's all the ones and a few of the zeros that were
in the original database at the first coin flip says we should keep around.
But now, sometimes we need to lie.
So sometimes we need to choose randomly.
So if one minus our first coin flip,
here's all the places where we want to actually choose randomly.
So all of these ones that you see here,
we want it to actually sample from the second coin flip.
So we can do this by simply sampling or multiplying times the second coin flip.
So here's all the values that are being sampled randomly.
So now, if we simply add these together,
then we get a new augmented database, which is differentially private.
Cool. So far so good.
So again, local differential privacy is all about adding noise to the database entries.
So that any queries that we do in
this database have a certain amount of differential privacy.
However, in doing so,
we have done something statistically significant.
So we might try to say we can just query the database and be done.
So torch.mean database.float and boom,
so we augment the database and we can just go ahead and use this.
However, something else has happened here.
So half of our values are honest and half of
our values are always going to have a mean or try to have a mean, that's at 0.5.
This means that it's going to skew the output of our query towards 0.5.
Because half the time,
we're using the values that are from the second coin flip,
which has a 50/50 chance of being positive or being heads or tails.
So let's just say the database had,
on average was 70 percent of the time that
people said true for whatever the taboo behavior was.
So this database is actual values reflecting from people.
Let's say that 70 percent of these were true,
so that the mean of this would be 0.7.
That would mean that if we took half the values from here and half the values
from this randomly generated 50/50 distribution,
then the mean of them would shift from this where
the mean was 0.7 and this where the mean was 0.5,
would be halves between them.
The mean would then be 0.6 even though the original distribution was 0.7.
Right. So it's almost like this query is now skewed as a result of the noise.
Skewing was not all we were after,
what we wanted to do was just give each individual person plausible deniability.
So we have to do one final step here, which is deskew the result.
So the interesting thing is here,
if we know that,
say for example, there's a distribution
here where there's a certain averages here and we'll say it's 70 percent.
The average of this is always going to be 50 percent.
So that we know that the average between these two datasets.
If we are half from here and half from here is 60 percent,
then we can just do that in reverse.
So that means that if the output of
our augmented database gives us a mean of 60 percent, well,
then, we know that it's really trying to tell us 70 percent
because half of our data is just 50/50 random noise.
So I can actually go and try to deskew this result.
This is the true output of our database.
Because I have removed the skewed average that was
a result of this local differential privacy or this second coin flips.
So this is actually the output of our augmented result,
so our augmented differentially private result. We'll call it db result.
So now, we can package all this as a single query and see what was in our assignments.
So in our assignment, we needed to return the augmented result,
that differentially private result.
We also want to return the true result,
because the notion of this and what we wanted to learn from this lesson is
actually to understand how these results tend to change.
So let's go ahead and return the true result or
compute the true result as well. Here we go.
Okay. So now, what we want to do here,
is work on databases at different sizes.
So I believe in the assignment we were supposed to do a database of size 10.
Then look at the private result, true results.
We'll print this out here so it's easy to see.
So with noise and without noise.
This is the true answer.
What we're going to see when we compare these, is that, man,
that noise really throws things off sometimes but let's use a bigger dataset.
Okay. That's quite a bit closer.
Let's use an even bigger dataset.
Now, we're getting really close.
Then, even bigger dataset.
So we'll put 10,000 entries and that is getting really close.
So here's the thing to remember,
about local differential privacy and
really actually about differential privacy in general,
whenever we're adding noise to a distribution, were corrupting it.
So the statistics that the queries that
we're doing are going to be sensitive to this noise.
However, the more data points that we have,
the more this noise will tend to average out.
It will tend to not affect the output of the query because on average,
across a large number of people,
sometimes the noise is making the result
higher than it should be or lower than the result should be.
But on average, it's actually still centered
around the same mean of the true data distribution.
In particular, a general rule of thumb, which
is local differential privacy is very data hungry.
In order to be able to noise the dataset, you're adding a ton of noise,
we're adding noise to every single value in the dataset.
So when we have 10,000 entries,
we're adding 10,000 bits of noise.
I guess like with 50 percent probability.
So it probably more like 5,000 bits of noise,
but that's still a lot of noise.
So global differential privacy, in contrast,
only adds noise to the output of the query.
We will find that this tends to be
quite a bit more accurate and a little less data hungry than local differential privacy.
So if you want to implement
local differential privacy and protect data at the data level,
protect the dataset itself.
Then, you'll want to use local differential privacy,
that we want to make sure you have a really large dataset.
Whereas, if you want to use
a less data hungry algorithms and
maybe your dataset is smaller but you still need to protect it,
then it's better to lean towards global differential privacy.
In general, I think personally leaning towards global differential privacy seems
to be where a lot of the field is going
although obviously the local db has its advantages.
So the event the local db is that in theory you could publish some of these datasets.
So you don't have to trust someone
to lower trust settings, but we'll get into those later.
But for now, just understand this notion of
this trade off between small datasets and and large datasets.
Meaning that your noise creates vastly different outputs of the queries,
versus only slightly different outputs of the queries
when you have a large enough dataset to average the noise over.