In this next project,
I want you to change this query and soup it up a bit.
This is a pretty challenging project.
This will be tough but the idea behind this project is
you get an intuitive sense for exactly what's going on under the hood,
and how the re-normalizing step is going to happen.
So what I'd like for you to do is to augment
the randomized response query from the previous project,
to allow for varying amounts of randomness to be added.
Specifically, I want you to be able to bias the first coin flip to be
higher or lower probability of outputting a one and then run the same experiment.
So what you're going to have to do here is to add a new parameter to the query function,
so that we'll now accept both of the database and some noise parameter,
which is a percentage.
The noise parameter should change how likely is for the first coin flip to be a one,
as opposed to zero.
Then, I want you to properly re-balanced
the result of the query given this adjustable parameter.
So again, this is a challenging project and of course,
I'd like for you to go ahead and experiment with a database of size a 100,
and then change the amount of noise and observe
the degree to which the query is made less accurate,
depending on how much noise you add.
Stick with it. It might not be one that everyone gets the first time,
but go ahead and jump in and in a second,
I'll show you how to implement this project myself.