So in this project, we're going to take the code that we wrote in
the last section and we're going to add one extra feature.
That extra feature is that we're going to make it so that we can bias
the first coin flip to be arbitrarily more likely or less likely to be heads.
The thing that we're going to need to change is how we actually
reskew the output of our mean query later.
So the first thing we're going to do is go ahead and copy this query.
So this is the code that we had from last time.
We have this first coin flip and we determine
the likelihood of this coin flip to be a heads or tails based on this threshold.
So the torch code here actually,
these outputs, a random distribution of numbers between zero and one.
So if we look at here,
it's a bunch of random numbers,
just uniformly random between zero and one.
We threshold it so that say 50 percent of them
on average are above the threshold and 50 percent are below.
So now, what we want to do in this section is we want to make this adjustable.
We want to make this a noise parameter which actually
sets the likelihood that the coin flip will be a heads.
So let's say 0.2, maybe 0.2 percent probability of being a heads.
So how does these change things?
The interesting thing here is all the rest of the pieces are really the same.
So the first coin flip, we've modified with this a little bit.
The second coin flip is still a random distribution between a 50/50 coin flip,
just sometimes we're more or less likely to actually rely on
the second coin flip depending on
the likelihood that our first coin flip is a heads or tails.
Augmented database is still created in the same way
because it's still based on these two coin flips.
The part that's different however is how we reskew the results for this mean query later.
Because the nature of this average is based on
the idea that we are reskewing the data set to have the same average,
to have the same mean as the original database.
We take whatever the actual database was.
So in one example earlier,
we mentioned that perhaps 70 percent of people on
average answered true to whatever the question was.
We take whatever this distribution is so that we'll say it's centered around
0.7 and we average it with a distribution that is centered around 0.5,
then that returns a distribution if they're weighted evenly that's averaged around 0.6.
So we had a true distribution mean,
let's just say it was 0.7.
Then we say that our noise distribution,
we'll say it's 0.5 because it's a random coin flip.
A 70 percent of people said yes to our question,
and then 50/50 coin flip.
So this means that the augmented database mean is going to
be "true_dist mean times noise_dist_ mean divided by two."
Oh, plus, sorry. However, we want to get rid of this random noise
on average while still keeping the noise that we actually put on each individual entry.
More importantly, if we are more or less likely to choose as distribution,
we want to make sure that however we reskew this so that the means are correct,
we can properly deskew it according to this noise parameter.
What we really do here is we actually sort of run this mean in reverse.
We're unaveraging the output of the query.
So we'll go ahead and pop this out so we can work with it out here.
So this is the one we're going to work with.
First, we're going to create a sort of in which it's actually our skewed query.
So the output of our query.
So our skewed result,
which equals augmented database dot float dot mean.
So it's a skewed result. So this is the wrong result.
We need to basically unaverage this with 0.5.
It's being averaged at 0.5 but it's a weighted average and
that weighted average according to this weight.
Yeah, let's talk about this analogy down here just a little bit longer.
So if we say our noise parameter is 0.2,
in our original example,
this was 50/50 first coin flip,
which meant that 50 percent of the time,
we use the true distribution with a mean of 0.7,
and 50 percent of the time,
we use a distribution that also had 0.5.
So another way of thinking about this is that
our true distribution mean was being multiplied by noise.
So half of the time, we're using this distribution,
and the other half of the time,
we were using noise distribution mean one minus noise.
So how do we then reverse this?
Well, basically we can do simple algebra and pull out
what the true distribution mean was by removing all these other terms.
For de-using all these different terms.
It's going to be a multiplications attraction component because we want to get
out this value or at least deskew this value according to these others.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So the way in which we do this is we say,
we take our skewed result,
and we say our final or augments result or private result is going
to equal our skewed result divided by our noise minus 0.5,
and the 0.5 is this 0.5 right here.
Then, we're going to multiply this times noise divided by one minus noise.
The deal that's going on right here is what
we're basically deskewing these results so that
our private result has its mean adjusted according to this noise parameter.
So this noise parameter was at 0.5,
then the skewed result,
the distance between a skewed result and the private result is basically
this is halfway between the true mean of distribution,
and the mean of the distribution of 50/50 coin flip.
So notice that 0.5.
So 0.5 minus 0.4929, 0.5 minus 0.4858.
This is roughly half of this,
so we're doubling the distance because there was a 50/50 average.
So as we can see, this is the correct algebraic deskewing formula.
Then we return to the same things we did before.
Okay. Now, we want to do a similar experiment to what we did last time.
However, instead of varying the size of the database,
we want to vary the amount of noise that we're adding to the database.
So we're going to keep the database, I think it was the size of 100.
Then, we're going to have this noise parameter.
Let's start at like 0.1,
it's relatively low noise 0.2,
and we're just going to keep doubling and see what happens.
It's changing less than I expected. Oh, we do not run this.
There we go. It's changing quite a bit less than expected,
actually. Let's just keep going.
Typo. Results. As we increase the amount of noise,
the difference between on average starts getting quite a bit more.
But if we counter this with a large dataset,
then they come back together.
So the size of the data set allows you to add more noise or
more privacy protection to
the individuals who are inside the dataset. This is an interesting trade-off.
The counter-intuitive thing here is that the more private data you have access to,
the easier it is to protect the privacy of the people who were involved.
So the larger this corpus of dataset is,
the more noise you can add while still getting an accurate result.
Now, in society, this is actually probably even more counter-intuitive
because people think of preserving privacy is
as giving statistician's access to less and less data,
but in fact, with differential privacy,
the opposite is true.
Because the intuition behind differential privacy is about
saying we want to learn about an aggregation over a large corpus.
We want to learn something that is common about many different people.
So one thing might be,
let's say you're performing statistical analysis of medical records.
Let's say you're going to identify tumors inside of MRI scans.
You have a collection of say 1,000 images that have
the tumors annotated so you're trying to learn how to
detect tumors inside of individuals.
When you're performing a statistical analysis,
you're not actually interested in whether any one of these people has a tumor.
Now, you're not trying to violate any particular person's privacy, instead,
you're trying to do a statistical study to understand what do tumors in humans look like.
You're actually trying to go after information that is fundamentally public but just
happens to be buried inside of individual private data points.
More importantly, the way in which
this technology works is that the differential privacy is a very complex kind of
filter and the way that the differentially private filter works is that it
looks for information that is consistent across multiple different individuals.
It tries to filter out perfect differential privacy
so no information leakage would, in theory,
be able to block out any information that is unique about participants in
your dataset and only let through
information that is consistent across multiple different people,
aka allowing you to learn what do tumors in humans look like
without learning whether any individual person
that you were studying actually had a tumor.
That's the nature of this kind of a filter that differential privacy allows us to have.
But it's only allowed to look for repeating statistical information inside the dataset.
So if you have a really small data set,
the odds of it finding the same statistical pattern twice
are actually pretty low because you only have a few people to look at.
If you have a dataset of five images,
every image is totally unique,
everything's going to look like it's totally private information,
differential privacy will have to get rid of all the data,
it won't let anything through,
even a small amount of noise will totally corrupt the output of your query.
However, if you have say a million images or maybe,
in this case, we have 10,000 entries,
then it becomes a lot easier to learn
about general characteristics in the dataset because you have
more data points to look at and compare with each other
to look for a similar statistical information.
So what are differentially private mechanisms?
They're mechanisms that study a dataset and filter out
any information that is unique to individual points
in your dataset and try to let through information that is
consistent across multiple different people in your dataset.
This is why one of the big takeaways from this project in
this lesson is really that the larger the corpus of information that you can work with,
the easier it is for you to protect privacy because it's easier for your algorithm to
detect that some statistical information is happening in more than one person,
and thus is not private or unique or sensitive to that person
because it's a general characteristic of humans more and more generally.
So it gets a little bit of the philosophy differential privacy.
In the next lesson, we'll really unpack what this means a bit more formally.