Thus far, we've gotten a lot of intuitive notions of privacy.
We've walked through an example of local differential privacy,
we've walked through a differencing attack,
we've walked through basic queries and the definition of sensitivity.
Now, we have the basic building blocks,
talk about what the true formalized definition of differential privacy actually is.
This will also lead us into
our first implementation of global differential privacy as well.
In particular, we're going to look at global differential privacy and ask the question,
how much noise should we add after the query has been run to
sort of noise up the entire query your database with one block of noise?
We will find that this global differential privacy will also intuitively relate
quite nicely to the formal definition of
differential privacy, which we'll propose along the way.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to create a database with
our query and then analyze it with the formal definition of DP.
We're going to add noise to the output of
our function and we have two different kinds of noise that we can add,
Laplacian noise or Gaussian noise.
In order to know how much noise we should add,
we will appear to the formalized definition of DP.
This is the definition proposed by Cynthia Dwork.
It's the e equals mc squared of differential privacy.
It's most important formula in the field and it
doesn't create differential privacy necessarily,
it's not a method of adding noise per say.
Instead, it's a constraint so that you can analyze a query with
noise and know whether or not this query and noise is leaking too much information.
In particular, we have two different measures called Epsilon and Delta,
and these compose a threshold for leakage.
Now, let me unpack this a little bit for you what this exact inequality is.
So the previous method of adding noise that we
just worked with in the last session was called
local differential privacy because we added noise to each datapoint individually.
This is necessary for some situations where in the data is so sensitive
that individuals do not trust them that noise will be added later.
However, it comes at a very high costs in terms of accuracy.
So if you'll remember back to how we actually constructed the coin flipping example,
you'll remember that before an individual gave us their answer,
you would query an individual and you would say, hey,
are you performing some sort of let's say activity?
Before they gave you they're true or false value,
they would actually flip their coin at that point and so that means that they
were adding noise themselves to their individual datapoint
before submitting it to you and it's this local term
refers to the fact that they are locally
adding noise to the data before it gets sent to you.
Now, if you're familiar with the intuitions of say dataset anonymization,
even though dataset anonymization is a broken technique and you should use it,
it's probably the closest parallel to local differential privacy to the extent that it is
augmenting datapoints individually with the intent of trying to build release.
But again, don't do dataset anonymization,
don't advocate people to do dataset anonymization
because it's a fundamentally broken idea.
However, this leads us directly into the other kind or
the other class of differential private algorithms called global differential privacy.
Global differential privacy instead of adding noise to individual datapoints,
applies noise to the output of a function on datapoints.
The advantage in general,
and is a little bit of a sweeping statement,
but the advantage in general is that you can often add a lot less noise and get
a much more accurate result if you
wait to add the noise until after you've computed a function,
and the reason for this is that many functions actually reduce the sensitivity involved.
So for example, here we have a query or a database.
So local differential privacy would add noise here,
and this is what we did in the last session we were adding a little bit of noise to
individual datapoints for the sake
of protecting when we were simulating the coin flipping example.
Have a global differential privacy would add noise out here to the output of a function.
Now, this doesn't have to be just a single function,
this can be a big long chain of functions,
it could be a sum and a threshold and then another some and then multiplication or any
any number of functions that we wanted to chain together and we can add
noise in the middle or at the end wherever we wanted to do this.
As a general rule of thumb,
as you process data more and more,
it is quite common for sensitivity to go down.
So a good place to start,
if you're trying to figure out where you want to add
noise in your system and your pipeline,
is to lean more towards doing it as late in
the chain as possible because the later you go,
the more individuals you have likely aggregated over,
the more processing you have done, the more likely you will have
done to do thresholds or squishing
functions like [inaudible] or any other kinds of post-processing on your data.
The better the chances are that you'll do things that actually
reduce some sensitivity and actually end up
reducing the amount of noise that you have to add giving you
a more accurate result with less privacy leakage.
So just these are a few general statements that I'm making about
global and local differential privacy and why people prefer one over the other.
So if the data is so sensitive,
the people aren't going to give it to you then people tend to lean more towards
local differential privacy because the individual data owners are just
sort of so scared that they want to protect their data before they handed over to what's
called a trusted curator, who is the party that is
generally referred to as the one who's actually performing differential privacy.
That's the reason that most people use local DP, use
local differential privacy whereas people who use
global differential privacy when they're more interested in saying,
"Hey, I really need the output of this to be
accurate while still having the same level of privacy".
So if there's a trade-off between how
much the data owner is willing to trust the person performing differential privacy here.
So if you can facilitate a setup, where differential privacy is being
performed over a large dataset
and they can trust the you're performing differential privacy correctly,
I would strongly advocate for you to lean
towards global differential privacy because it can
be a much more accurate method of stripping out private information.
So enough on global local differential privacy
both of these lead to the next question of
how do we actually measure how much privacy is
being leaked inside of a differentially private algorithm?
This leads us to the formal definition of differential privacy.
So even though up to this point,
I've for the sake of making an intuitive,
I've been giving intuitive explanations and
sort of high-level intuitions on
how differential privacy works, what it's really all about.
Differential privacy itself, the term
differential privacy. It's actually a very formalized definition.
There's actually multiple definitions.
There are multiple proposed definitions of differential privacy.
The one we're going to be talking about today is
the one that has been proposed by Cynthia Dwork.
It's actually the most well-known,
the most widely used and other forms of differential privacy typically build on
top of this one for one purpose or another purpose.
So, this is a great place to start and many of the terms and
the techniques that we would mentioning here are
also relevant to other forms of differential privacy.
So, let's walk through this definition.
A randomized algorithm M with domain natural numbers absolute value of x.
So, this is basically saying a certain set of
natural numbers is epsilon delta differentially private,
if for all S in the range of M and for all x,
y in an X such that x minus y is less than or equal to 1.
Okay. So, let's reread this a bit more intuitively.
A randomized algorithm M,
M being a randomized algorithm is this.
This would be a globally differential private randomized algorithm.
It's some sort of function on a database with some sort of noise added to it.
Now, this noise could have been inside the db or applied to
the db in here which in case it would have been locally differentially private.
So, where the noise is actually added,
the exact characteristics and this mechanism is nonspecific here.
So, this this could be any function.
We have we don't know what algorithm is S,
we just know that it has the ability to query
a database and it is randomized in some way.
Okay. So, that's what we know about M. Oh yes,
and it has an output domain of Nx.
Meaning it could be a histogram over certain entries in database.
So, it's discretized in this particular case and we're saying that this
is epsilon delta differentially private if
for all the potential things that it could predict.
Right, so for all for things S in the range of M and for all database pairs.
So, parallel of databases such that x minus y is less than equal to 1.
Actually, these are these are histograms over pair databases.
So, this is saying, okay,
database has a bunch of stuff in it, right?
And Mx counts how many times each thing happened in the database right?
So, how many times it was a database full of marbles.
I don't know, in each each entry had a marble of a specific color.
This might count the number of red marbles and blue marbles,
the number of yellow marbles right in which case,
this would be three natural numbers and the size of x would be
three and of course their natural numbers because we're counting individual things.
So, things, it's something to take away. Its discretized,
the differential privacy definition is post in the form of a histogram over a database.
Okay, and so we're saying there are two histograms right,
and the max distance between these two histograms is one.
Meaning that they only differ in one entry.
Meaning that, that they are parallel databases.
So, the databases that formed the histograms are parallel.
Okay. So, let's just walk through this one more time just to
make sure that you understand this setup. This definition.
A randomized algorithm m with a domain Nx meaning that is it's their natural numbers,
the x and actually earlier in this paper,
it was identified that this was referring specifically to a histogram over
database is epsilon delta differentially private if,
for all the things that M could predict,
so all the all the potential outputs of m for all and
for all the potential inputs that are
parallel databases right and this is the part of the thing.
It's parallel. That this constraint is true.
Okay. So, the setup is two histograms.
One is the full database.
One is database with one entry missing and this constraint is true.
So, what is this constraint?
Let's start with what we know.
m to the x is actually taking our mechanism and running it over this histogram.
My is doing the same thing over any for every parallel database right.
So, it's every database, well, any database.
We'll say any database. Any database with one entry missing right.
So, this threshold has to be true for all databases.
But, it's only actually expressing one at a time right.
But we're saying that it's true for all databases and so okay.
So, we've got the query over other parallel database,
we got query over the full database right,
and it's returning something in S. Okay.
So, S is one of the possible things that it could be predicting.
One of the things in the range M right.
Now, we're saying that this is true for all things,
but you can think about it intuitively in your head as you know
for predicting the the red marble.
So, what is the distance between the distribution over all the things in the database,
the probability distribution over all things database
versus the probability distribution over all the things in the database minus one entry.
So, random distribution over things in the database, objects in the database.
Random distribution over objects in the database with one entry missing.
Now, the question that we want to ask,
the question that is that the core focus of
differential privacy is how different are these two distributions?
How different is the output of my mechanism that the prediction of my mechanism,
when I remove an entry from the database?
How much does it change from here to here?
And the measurement of the maximum amount that these two distributions are
different is measured by two parameters.
Epsilon and delta.
E to the power of epsilon constrains how different these distributions are.
Sort of the primary constraint we might say,
and some algorithms actually only use epsilon.
So, here we say,
if epsilon was zero and these distributions are identical,
we're going to ignore delta for a second right.
So, if epsilon is zero,
then e to the epsilon is one,
and these distributions are identical right.
So this is less than or equal to would be equal two.
Now, since epsilon zero,
we would say is perfect privacy.
Epsilon zero delta zero would be perfect privacy.
So, if this constraint was satisfied at epsilon zero delta zero,
then we have no privacy leakage with M on x.
So, by computing the output of this randomized mechanism.
However, let's say epsilon was 1.
Okay. Well, that allows some privacy leakage.
Exactly, how much that is, we can get to that in a minute.
But, something that is very important to take away is
that something can satisfy differential privacy.
Can satisfy this constraint,
but still leak private information right.
So, leaking or not, leaking is not an all or nothing kind of thing.
You can actually leak small amounts of statistical information.
Now, delta is the probability,
which is usually very small.
The probability that you will accidentally leak
more information than epsilon claims that you will leak.
So, delta is often you know,
0.00001 or something like that or it's zero,
it's usually a very very small probability when it's
non-zero and it's basically saying hey,
most of the time,
you're able to keep everything underneath this amount of leakage.
These distributions are going to be very very
going to be at least as close most of the time,
but only this probability will they actually not be,
and this is basically saying that, if your query
is for just the right thing with just the right random noise some probability,
you will accidentally leak more information.
So, this is the constraint of differential privacy and so as you might imagine,
a tremendous amount of effort goes into developing really good random algorithms.
So, I said this can be satisfied in a way that is useful right.
So, where we get the most accurate output of our queries possible
with the lowest epsilon and delta possible and there are also
improvements or modifications to this algorithm or this constraint that seek to
modify it in various ways which you can observe
for literature and and will lead to some pointers to at the end of the course.
So, things to note about this setup.
So, first and foremost,
this is looking at one query.
So, this is one query against the database.
If you have multiple queries,
this is not what this is supporting.
Multiple queries would would have to have a build on this and
we can talk about how that actually happens in a minute right.
So, this is the sort of epsilon delta budget
which I'll also sometimes referred to as your privacy budget,
is satisfied for one query using this particular constraint.
Okay. So, in the next video,
we're actually going to look at how to actually add
noise for global differential privacy.
So, we can say okay,
given that we want to be able to satisfy
this constraint for a particular query against a database,
how much noise should we add to make sure
that we don't spend more than a certain level of epsilon.
So, don't move on from this video and rewatch it if you have
two until you get an intuitive sense for what epsilon
and delta are all about because they are crucially
important to differential privacy and to the next project that we're going to tackle.