In this concept, we're going to answer the question,
how do we actually use epsilon and delta?
We're going to learn how to take a query and at a certain degree of
noise to make what we call a randomized mechanism.
We want this randomized mechanism to satisfy a certain degree of differential privacy.
We went to augment a query like a sum, threshold,
mean or average and add a certain amount of noise to
this query so that we get a certain amount of differential privacy.
In particular, we're going to leave behind
the local differential privacy previously discussed,
and instead opt for global differential privacy.
As I mentioned earlier, the difference between local and
global is that global differential privacy adds noise to
the output of a query while local differential privacy
adds noise to each data input to the query.
So given that we are going for global dP,
we're adding noise to the output and how much noise should we add?
We're going to add the minimum amount required to
satisfy a certain level of epsilon and delta,
which we will term our privacy budget for a given query.
Now, in order to do this, there are
two types of noise we could add as I mentioned earlier;
Gaussian noise or Laplacian noise.
Generally speaking, Laplacian noise works better but technically
both are still valid and can give us varying levels of epsilon-delta privacy.
In this case, we're going to exclusively focus on Laplacian.
Now, to the hard question.
How much noise should we add?
The amount of noise necessary to add to the output of
the query is a function of four things.
First, the amount of noise is dependent on the type of noise that we're adding.
We're just going to focus on Laplacian here, so that one's easy.
Second, we must take into account the sensitivity
of the query that we are using to query the database.
As mentioned, some queries are way more
sensitive to removing a person from the database and other queries.
Some sensitivity is very consistent sensitivity,
as in every database always has the same level of sensitivity for that query type.
Whereas some queries, have
varying levels of sensitivity that is dependent on the database.
Then of course, the two other things we must take into
account is the desired epsilon and delta.
Thus, for each type of noise that we're adding,
we have a different way of calculating how much noise to add as a function of
the sensitivity of the query to meet a certain epsilon-delta constraint.
So to restate this,
each noise type has a specific function, which tells
us how much noise to add given a certain sensitivity, epsilon and delta.
For Laplacian noise, this function is the following.
Laplacian noise takes an input parameter beta,
which determines how significant the noise is.
We set the beta by taking the sensitivity of
the query and dividing it by the epsilon that we want to achieve.
As it happens, delta is always zero for Laplacian noise,
so we can just ignore it.
In other words, if we set beta to be this value when creating our Laplacian noise,
then we know we will have a privacy leakage which is
less than or equal to a certain amount of epsilon.
Furthermore, the nice thing about Laplacian noise is that we
don't have to worry about delta because it's always set to zero.
Gaussian noise has a non-zero delta,
which is why it's somewhat less desirable.
Thus, we're using Laplacian for this exercise.
There's this really awesome proof for why this is the case but that proof is
not necessary to know how to use Laplacian noise.
Furthermore, when reading literature about differential privacy,
you've heard the term Laplacian mechanism,
which refers to a function being augmented with Laplacian noise in this way,
forming the mechanism " [inaudible] " in
the original and differential privacy function discussed earlier.
The thing we need to know here however is that we can take
any query for which we have a measure of sensitivity,
choose any arbitrary epsilon budget that we want to preserve and we can
add the appropriate amount of Laplacian noise to the alphabet of the query, pretty neat.
In the next project, I want you to do this yourself.
First, modify a query for some with the appropriate amount of
Laplacian noise so that you can satisfy a certain epsilon delta constraint.
So this new some query should automatically add
the appropriate noise given an arbitrary epsilon level.
For Laplace, you can use the Laplace function np.random.laplace.
After you had this mechanism working for the sum function,
I then want you to do the same thing for the mean function.
Scaling the Laplacian noise correctly given the fact that,
mean has a different level of sensitivity than sum.
So in this lesson, we're going to learn about how to take a query and add
varying amounts of noise so that it satisfies a certain degree of differential privacy.
In particular, we're going to leave behind the local differential privacy we've
previously discussed and instead opt to focus on global differential privacy.
So as you may remember, since
Global differential privacy adds noise to the output of the query.
In this lesson, we're going to focus on learning
how much noise we should add to the output of the query,
so that it satisfies
a certain epsilon-delta differential privacy threshold
based on the formula that we learned in the last lesson.
So now, the question is,
how much noise should we add?
Well, the amount of noise necessary to add to the output of
the query is a function of four different things.
The first is the type of noise that want to use,
the most common types are Gaussian or Laplacian noise.
Which is simply just two different distributions that we can sample random numbers from.
The second, is the sensitivity of the query or
function that we're adding the noise to the output off, right?
So if we're adding noise to the output of
a sum query that might have a sensitivity of one,
then that would cause us to add a certain degree of noise.
But if we're adding noise to a different query that has a different sensitivity,
then we would add a different amount of noise, right?
The third thing is the desired level of epsilon that
we want to make sure they are next query is beneath.
Fourth, the desired delta, the one that stay beneath.
So these are our constraints on the amount of
privacy leakage that we're want to allow and then this
is the sensitivity or the king of function that we're adding
noise to the output of and is the type of noise we are adding to.
With these four things,
we can figure out how much noise we should add and actually
properly build a randomized mechanism.
So thus, for each type of noise we're adding,
we have a different way of calculating how much to add as
a function of sensitivity, epsilon and delta.
We're going to focus on Laplacian noise.
So Laplacian noise, increase and decrease according to a scale parameter beta.
Before I get to you, there are wide variety of different kinds of randomized mechanisms.
In this course, we're only going to go
through a small handful of them and I highly encourage you,
when you do finish this course,
to Google around and learn some more about the different kinds of differential
private randomized mechanisms that can be appropriate for different use cases.
Okay. So back to Laplacian noise.
So Laplacian noise is the amount of noise you're adding for
a Laplacian distribution is increased or decreased according to a scale parameter beta.
We choose beta based on the following formula.
B or beta equals the sensitivity of our query.
That's the query that we are adding this noise to,
divided by epsilon, right?
This epsilon again, we're spending this epsilon for every query, right?
So if we're querying a database, right?
Every time we do it,
we're going to spend this amount of epsilon, right?
So the notion here is that we have a certain epsilon budget that
we wanted to stay underneath and that by using this simple formula,
we can know how much noise we have to add to the output of these queries in
order to make sure that we are preserving privacy.
So in other words, if we set b this value, b this value,
that we know that we'll have a privacy leakage of less than or equal to epsilon.
The nice thing about Laplacian noise is that it actually guarantees that
we do this with a delta that is equal to zero, right?
So we have these four things right here.
So type of noise, sensitivity, epsilon-delta.
Laplacian noise always has a delta that's zero.
So if you remember, delta was a probability that we would
accidentally leak more than this amount of epsilon, right?
So Laplacian is guaranteed to not leak more than this amount of epsilon.
Now, one other question you might have,
what happens if we want to query repeatedly?
Well, as it happens,
if we do query repeatedly,
then we can simply add the epsilons across the different queries.
So if we have epsilon of say five,
we could do five queries that leak epsilon of value one for example.
This is how the Laplacian mechanism works.
In the next section, what I would like for you to do is actually
perform a sum and a mean query, right?
So you can take the sum and the mean query over
the database and use the ones we used previously in the course.
I want you to add a certain amount of Laplacian noise to the output,
so that you're underneath a certain level epsilon.
In the next lesson, I'll show you how I would do this.
See you then.