So in this video,
we're actually going to be putting together a Laplacian mechanism,
a Laplacian randomize mechanism,
which we are going to use to perform two different kinds of queries; sum and mean.
We're going to see that the way in which we choose our Beta's,
the ways in which the we formulate the amount of Laplacian noise to
create is adjusted based on the sensitivity of sum and mean.
Such that for mean,
which has a smaller sensitivity,
we end up adding a smaller amount of noise.
So let's jump in.
First, we're going to say our Epsilon budget for our single query is going to be 0.5,
and now we're going to import numpy as np,
and let's create a database, which we're going to query.
As you will remember,
all of these databases are the ones and zeros.
So this is how we know that the sensitivity of addition is only one.
So because if I were to say the sum is 54,
but the maximum amount that this could change,
if I remove anyone of these entries, it'll be one.
But if this database were a database of two's,
0-2, well then the sensitivity would actually double to two.
Because the maximum amount of
the output would change if I removed entry could be as high as two.
But in particular, because we know this sort of
apiary knowledge about a database is all zeros and ones,
just counting the specific entries in the database,
we can know that our sensitivity for sum is simply one.
So let's jump into our first query,
which is simply the sum over the database.
So let's create our mechanism.
So sum_query, mechanism m,
the source of randomized mechanism.
So what else we see? Laplacian mechanism.
We have database and we have our query.
So Laplacian mechanism.
Actually, let's go ahead and put in sensitivity of a query.
So now, the first thing we want to do is we need to
calculate what the Beta should be for a Laplacian noise.
So we're going to say Beta equals sensitivity divided by Epsilon.
So as you might remember, this is how we calculate the correct Beta for Laplacian noise,
and then we're going to say the amount of noise is equal to,
I got to convert it to, let's see,
what are the type was this?
Okay, torch.tensor.
So we're sampling values from zero to one,
and according to this Beta spread parameter,
this query is actually this function,
query database, plus noise.
This is our Laplacian mechanism.
So let's use it, let's try it out.
So laplacian_mechanism database some_query and sensitivity of one.
As you can see every time we create it,
it's a little bit different.
The true answer is 54.
So as you can see when we run this,
it's just above and below 54. Pretty cool.
I think I might have said that this was between zero and one.
So Laplacian, it's not a range between zero and one,
this is actually a mean centered at
zero and then Beta is controlling the amount of spread.
So now let's do this for a mean query.
So def mean_query db equals db_sum,
let's say, we just do torch.mean.
Awesome. We have a 100 entries in our dataset.
So the thing here is, now we know that
the sensitivity is actually going to be one divided by 100,
because it's the max amount that the entry could
change divided by the total number of entries,
because that's the output of the query if you divide it by that.
So this sensitivity is much smaller for me.
So if we were to use our Laplacian mechanism on the mean query,
it's one divided by 100.
So now, as you can see the noise is much smaller.
The noise is just a 100th smallest,
it's quite a bit smaller.
Whereas if you see this,
this one bounces around by multiple values;
54, 53, 57, 51,
so the noise is actually quite larger.
Whereas, the noise here is much smaller,
which is also appropriate because the output is also quite smaller.
Now, the next thing to also remember is that
this Epsilon is measuring the Epsilon that we are spending per query.
So let's say, we had a whole budget,
there was an Epsilon of say five,
then we wouldn't need to partition this.
We could do 10 queries and each with Epsilon constraint of 0.05.
So now, let's try something else.
So now if I say Epsilon equals 0.00001,
a very, very, very small Epsilon.
So almost no leakage. Watch what happens to this.
So previously, it was dancing around the 0.54 range.
But now, it's all over the place.
You see how much random is that this is because we're not leaking hardly any information,
because basically we're just returning a really big Laplacian distribution,
and same for this Laplacian mechanism.
So as we tutor Epsilons and make our Epsilon lower,
we're actually increasing the amount of noise that we have to add in order to be
able to get this really constraining level of privacy protection.
So the other interesting thing to remember
is that this is the same exact relationship that we
saw when we were working with local differential privacy in the context of coin flipping.
So the more noise that we added, the more protection,
the more plausible deniability that we gave each participant in our survey,
the more randomize our results we're looking.
The more randomize our analysis ended up being,
and the more individuals we needed to actually work
over in order to be able to get accurate statistics.
So similarly here, if we
have mechanisms functions on our data-set that have smaller sensitivity,
we can actually add less noise overall,
simply because we're asking for a function that's just less sensitive.
This function doesn't naturally try to leak as much information.
So we still have this really close relationship between sensitivity,
privacy leakage, and the number of entries in a database,
and the accuracy of the output result.
So it's a trade-off between these four different things,
and that's really important understand how this trade-off
works when we actually use this mechanism in the real world.
So I hope you've enjoyed working with this project.
In the next section we're going to jump into
some more different mechanisms and ways you can use differential privacy.