In the last few lessons, you might have been wondering,
what does all this have to do with deep learning?
Well, it turns out the same techniques that we were just studying formed
the core principles for how
differential privacy provides guarantees in the context of deep learning.
Previously, we defined perfect privacy as something like,
a query to a database returns
the same value even if we remove any person from that database.
If we're able to do that,
then no person is really contributing information
to the final query and their privacy is protected.
We use this intuition in the description of epsilon delta.
In the context of deep learning,
we have a similar standard, which is based on these ideas,
which instead of querying a database,
we're training a model.
Our definition of perfect privacy would then be something like,
training a model on a dataset should return
the same model even if we remove any person from the training dataset.
So we've replaced, "querying a database with training a model on a dataset".
In essence, the training process is actually a query,
but one should notice that this adds two points of
complexity, which the databases didn't have.
First, do we always know where people are referenced in a training dataset?
In a database, every row corresponded to a person,
so it was very easy to calculate the sensitivity because we can just remove individuals.
We knew where all of them were.
However, in a training dataset,
let's say I'm training a sentiment classifier on movie reviews,
I have no idea where
all the people are reference inside of that training dataset because,
it's just a bunch of natural language.
So in some cases,
this can actually be quite a bit more challenging.
Secondly, neural models rarely ever trained to the same state,
the same location even when they're trained on the same dataset twice.
So if I train the same deep neural network twice,
even if I train over the exact same data,
the model is not going to train to the same state.
There's already an element of randomness in the training process.
So, how do we actually prove or create
training setups where differential privacy is present?
The answer to the first question by default seems to be,
to treat each training example as a single separate person.
Strictly speaking, this is often a bit
overzealous as many examples have no relevance to people at all,
but others may have multiple partial individuals contained within that training example.
Consider an image, which has multiple people contained within it,
localizing exactly where people are referenced,
thus how much the model would change if those people will remove,
could be quite challenging.
But obviously, there's a technique we're about to talk about that tries to overcome this.
The answer to the second question regarding how
models rarely ever trained at the same location,
how do we know what sensitivity truly is,
has several interesting proposed solutions as well which we'll be discussing shortly.
But first, let's suppose
a new scenario within which we want to train a deep neural network.
As mentioned previously, privacy preserving technology is ultimately about
protecting data owners from individuals or parties they don't trust.
We only want to add as much noise as is necessary to
protect these individuals as adding excess noise needlessly hurts the model accuracy,
or failing to add enough noise might expose someone to privacy risk.
Thus, when discussing tools with differential privacy,
it's very important to discuss it in the context of
different parties who either do or do not trust each other,
so that we can make sure that we're using an appropriate technique.