To ground our discussion of differentially private deep learning,
let's consider a scenario.
Let's say you work for a hospital,
and you have a large collection of images about your patients.
However, you don't know what's in them.
You would like to use images develop
a neural network which can automatically classify them.
However, since your images aren't labeled,
they aren't sufficient to train a classifier.
Whoever, being a cunning strategist,
you realize that you can reach out to 10 partner hospitals,
which do have annotated data.
It is your hope to train your new classifier on
their datasets so you can automatically label your own.
While these hospitals are interested in helping,
they have privacy concerns regarding information about their own patients.
Thus, you will use the following technique to train a classifier
which protects the privacy of the patients in the other hospitals.
So first, you'll ask each of the 10 hospitals to train a model on their own datasets,
so generating 10 different models.
Second, you'll then use each of these 10 partner models to predict on
your local dataset generating
10 labels for each of your datapoints for each of your images.
Then, for each local datapoint, now with 10 labels,
you will perform a differentially private query to
generate a final true label for each example.
This query will be a max function,
where max is the most frequent label
across the 10 labels assigned for each individual image.
We will then need to add Laplacian noise to make this
differentially private to a certain epsilon delta constraint.
Finally, we will then retrain a new model on our local dataset,
which now has these labels that we have automatically generated.
This will be our final differentially private model.
So let's walk through these steps.
I will assume you are already familiar with
how to train and predicted deep neural network,
so we'll skip steps one and two and work with that example data.
We'll focus instead on step three,
namely how to perform the differentially private query for each example using toy data.