So before we jump in,
let's just walk through the exact scenario that we're working with one more time.
So the idea here is that,
we have an unlabeled dataset.
This is just a general assumption.
The assumption of this particular differential privacy framework.
There are other differential privacy frameworks out there,
but the assumption for this one is that we have an unlabeled dataset.
One plausible example where this exists,
is we represent a hospital,
and a hospital generates data.
Inside of our hospital,
we're collecting patient scans of a variety of conditions.
But this data isn't necessarily labeled.
No individual person has gone through and said,
does this particular scan have some particular phenomenon,
are these scans of males or females?
Or is there a specific kind of tumor?
Or a specific kind of other condition that is present in XYZ scan?
Some of them may have that, but some of them may not.
For now, we're going to assume that they don't.
They're just images of people.
What we want to be able to do us as a hospital,
is to have a machine learning model that can make predictions on this set of images.
So we're going to say these images are say radiology scans.
So they are are MRI's or CT scans or maybe an X-ray of a human body.
So it's just the X-ray of a human body and we as a hospital care
about identifying certain things in that X-ray,
where say there are 10 things we're interested in identifying.
However, our X-rays, our images aren't labeled.
So we can't train a machine learning model with our dataset.
Our dataset just isn't good enough.
We have the inputs but we don't have the outputs.
It's a bummer, so it's a bummer because we want people to have machine learning model,
we want to be able to serve our patients with the ability to automatically predict
these things as opposed to having to have doctors see every image.
So we say, what do we do?
Well, it turns out we know 10 other hospitals that do have this kind of annotated data.
However, they don't want to give it to us.
Maybe they're legally are not able to or if there's a competitive dynamic,
they don't actually just give us the data.
But they're willing to let us try something a bit more creative,
which is this particular framework.
The idea is, we want to somehow annotate our unlabeled data using their labeled data.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go to 10 different hospitals
and we're going to somehow pull out statistical signal
from their datasets to annotate
our datasets so that we can train our own machine learning model.
So it make sense? The way that we're going to do this is first,
we have each one of these partner hospitals train a model on their own datasets.
So all 10 hospitals train a model,
some machine learning classifier,
doesn't even matter what the classifier is,
whatever classifier they want to be able to using or, well,
your favorite one is either it's an SVM or
deep neural net or something, it doesn't matter.
Then we take their model and we predict it on our data.
So we take the model and we predict it on our dataset,
the one that is public to us,
the one that we're allowed to look at.
That generates 10 predictions for each of our images.
Why 10? Because there were 10 hospitals that we partnered with.
We trained 10 different models and we took all 10 of them and we predicted
them on each image, generating 10 labels.
Now, where the differential privacy piece comes in,
is we want to take their 10 labels and generate whichever label that they must agree on.
So we want to say, all right, there's 10 models they're voting,
which label is the most likely given that here are the votes.
So maybe if all 10 models said,
there's phenomenon number one in this image.
Well, then we would say okay, then it's the phenomenon one must be what it is.
But if half of them said it's phenomenon number three,
but another half said it's phenomenon number five,
then we would say 50/50 chance,
it could be one of these things, could be the other thing.
So this is exactly what we want to do.
We want to work with these 10 different hospitals,
they're going to train each model from their datasets,
we're going to bring those models to our dataset,
we're going to predict them over our dataset and then we want to
calculate the arg max over
their predictions on our data to figure out what the labels in our data
should be so that we can train our deep learning classifier, cool?
So the first training round where like a bunch of hospitals train a bunch of models,
that's just normal machine learning, normal deep learning.
So for the moment,
we're going to skip that part.
What I'm going to do instead,
is we're just going to synthesize
some fake versions of predictions they could have given us on our dataset.
So we're assuming that those parts already happened because I want to jump
straight into the differential privacy piece because that's the point of this lesson.
So the first thing we introduce input NumPy as np.
I'm going to say num teachers equals 10.
So these are, were working with 10 hospitals.
Num examples, so this is the size of our dataset,
num labels, the number of labels for a classifier.
We're assuming these are mutually exclusive at the moment.
It doesn't have to be this way but for the sake of argument,
we're just saying it can be one of 10 things but
it can't be multiples, you have to choose.
But you could do this with two labels,
100 labels, you could do it with multiple sets of two labels.
This is very generic,
we're just picking 10 out of thin air.
Now, we're going to synthetically generate a tensor,
where the number of rows is the number of teachers.
So we have 10 lists of numbers,
each coming from one of our teachers,
and there's 10,000 examples from each teacher. Why are they 10,000?
Because we took the classifier and we predicted
each teacher's classifier on every example that we have on our dataset, cool?
Now, just a little bit of NumPy stuff here and voila,
we have our synthetic datasets,
so fake labels, fake predictions.
So these are all the predictions from one teacher, all right?
Say there's 10,000 of them,
and these are all the examples for say the first image.
So this came from the first teacher,
this came from the second teacher, this came from the third teacher.
So the first teacher thought it was label four,
the second teacher thought it was labeled two,
the third teacher thought it was labeled nine, etc.
So now, what we care about, what we're trying to do,
is we're trying to in a deferentially private way,
combine these labels into a single label.
The reason that we want to do this is based on one core assumption,
and that core assumption is that these 10 partner hospitals, have different patients.
We're assuming they don't have overlapping patients,
maybe from different parts of the world,
maybe we just asked them and approved,
that they have an overlap applications.
This gets back to our core philosophy of differential privacy which is saying,
whenever we perform a query,
that query in theory is hypothetically, perfectly,
differentially private if the output of the query does
not change no matter what person I remove from the query.
However, in this particular case,
these don't represent individual people,
these represent whole collections of people.
So this prediction represents and it has information
transferring to it from a whole hospital worth of patients.
This has another whole hospitals with patients.
This has a whole another hospital with the patients.
So when we say combine this into one label,
the perfect way for us to do this would be
if the output of whatever and however we combine these labels,
in which case, we probably are going to take whichever one is most frequent.
We get the same prediction.
We get the same target,
the same output of our query regardless
of whether or not we remove one of these hospitals.
Because then, if that's our definition of robustness,
we would also know that we could remove any one of the patients from
those hospitals and the output of the query would be the same.
Because one patient is strictly a subset of the whole hospital.
If that doesn't totally make sense to you yet, it's okay,
we'll walk through this step-by-step and hopefully I'll make more sense as we go along.
So for now, all we want to do is take each image
and convert this vector
of predictions from all the different hospitals into a single prediction.
The way we're going to make that conversion is we're going to just
figure out which one did all of them agree on.
We're going to take what's called an arg-max.
So the first thing we need to do,
so this is an image,
closing one image where the predictions.
We're going to compute some label counts.
So NumPy has this nice thing called bind count and what it does,
it just goes through and counts the number of times it sees a certain integer.
So it looks like zero, one,
two was the most frequent number.
So if I look at an image one,
two, three, so yeah.
Two happen three times,
see how it counted and so we look at this,
we see the most frequent one is three.
So I could see it label counts.
So I could go NumPy.argmax and it will say two, well index two.
So which is the third one from the left.
So this is the most frequent label.
This is the one that all the hospital models agreed on.
So all the hospitals predicted our dataset on
this image and this was the most popular answer.
That these hospital models came back with.
However, this is not necessarily differentially private.
This is the exact answer from these hospitals.
However, we have interesting technique,
adding random noise to enforce a certain level of differential privacy and so for that,
we're going to turn back to our Laplacian mechanism.
So let's review this a bit.
So we'll say Epsilon,
let's set it to 0.1 for now,
Beta equals one divided by Epsilon,
and so we're going to say for i in range len label counts.
So for each label,
that's Laplacian noise and now,
we have a new set of loop counts.
So we actually took the counts and we're adding noise
to the counts. So does that makes sense?
So the counts is basically our mini database. All right.
So if you remember from before,
like we have a mini database across
these hospitals of label counts and we're going to add noise to each one of these counts,
and then we're going to perform arg max.
Now as you can see,
the noise actually made us get the wrong answer.
But this is something that we just have to be okay with.
So this is going to happen sometimes and our assumption is that later
on when our our deep neural net is training,
that it's going to filter through the sum of this noise,
look for all the ways that these agreed,
and it will learn how to predict reasonably accurately.
So this is new label. But this is not enough.
So this is just one image so what we actually need to
do is iterate through all of our images.
Let's go ahead and transpose this so just so we can iterate through
the rows for an image in prints.
New labels equals list,
iterate the whole thing, that was so fast.
So we have 10,000 new labels.
So we have now generated a synthetic dataset of
new labels based on the predictions from all of our partner hospitals.
Now, you might be wondering,
how much information did we leak?
So a super naive interpretation of this
could be just to add up
all these Epsilons but we wouldn't just have to add up these Epsilons,
we'd also have to add them up for every time that we used them.
So for every label counts.
So this would be something on the order of 100,000 times 0.1,
like could be massive.
That's not what we want.
The real innovative thing of PATE which we'll go over in the next section,
actually has a better derivation for how Epsilon is being spent in this model,
and it's very interesting,
quite fascinating, and so in the next section,
I'll show you what
this fancy PATE framework is
about and how we can actually get a better bound for this Epsilon.
But for now, if we were the hospital,
we had obtained these predictions at pennies labels and
generated these new labels for our dataset,
I would then go and train a deep learning model using all of
my X-ray images with these new synthesized labels
and I would know that I have spent under
my new model has fits underneath a certain Epsilon budget.
That the entire model itself
being a compression and a collection of all the Epsilons from
this dataset would be under a certain budget and in the next video,
we will actually learn just how low that budget can be. See you then.