In the last section, we generated a vector called new labels.
This was the output of our private data analysis.
Meaning that we had 10 different private datasets,
datasets from private sources that we computed complex function over,
to generate these new labels.
Now we're asking the question,
how much information would leak through these labels if we were to publish them?
If we were to just put them out on the Internet for anyone to see, like,
how much epsilon is actually present inside these labels?
The reason that we care about this is because our true goal is actually
train a deep learning model using these labels.
So we have a dataset of cells amount.
Remember we're a hospital that has our own x-ray scans.
These are our synthetically generated labels for these x-ray scans.
These labels came from private information.
So there's some amount of
information leakage that would be potentially inside of these new labels.
We want to answer the question,
how much epsilon is in total?
The reason that we care about this is,
this is really important property in differential privacy,
which is, it is immune to post-processing.
Meaning that if a dataset contains a certain amount of private information,
no amount of post-processing could divulge more information than was in the dataset.
So if the dataset has five epsilon worth of information in it,
no amount of post-processing on that would suddenly yield a dataset with six epsilon.
For example, you can't go up afterwards.
This is like an information theoretical bottleneck.
So it's like if I give you one bit of information about me,
you can't turn that into,
actually, in two bits.
If I give you one epsilon about me,
you can't turn that into two epsilon without
getting one epsilon about me from someone else.
So this immunity of post-processing is really important,
and this is why we care about these labels.
Because the ultimate claim we want to be able to say is, "Hey,
we as a hospital now have a deep learning model that
has a certain level of epsilon contained within,
or is underneath a certain level of epsilon at a privacy budget."
The way that we're doing that,
the way that PATE recommends that we do that is
instead of trying to train a Deep learning model directly,
that has a certain amount epsilon,
we first synthetically generate a dataset that has it at epsilon.
Then by extension, by this post-processing property of differential privacy,
we will also know that any Deep Learning model trained on
this dataset will also satisfy the same epsilon constraint.
So this is what we care about. Now when we look at this naive epsilon,
if we were simply just to add up all these epsilons,
we take the number of labels,
so 10 labels times the number of predictions, times our epsilon,
then we would get some massive epsilon that would just be exorbitant,
and we would never be able to publish.
However, the clever part of PATE is actually in its epsilon analysis.
So this is standard,
kind of Laplace noisy max mechanism.
But the PATE analysis is really where this algorithm shines.
Here's where the analysis actually starts to happen.
So let's just say, for example,
we have one image worth of labels that came from our 10 different hospitals.
So we're going to say labels equals num.array.
We'll say, the first hospital labeled one of our images,
so we're working with just one of our images in the system.
So the first hospital took our image,
read it to their classifier and said, "I think it's labeled nine."
Second hospital said nine again,
third hospital said three,
the fourth hospitals said six,
and then nine, and then nine,
and then nine, and then nine, and then eight.
How many are they? One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Then this one said two.
So now the question is, which one do we think it is?
Well, clearly we think it's a nine.
So nine was the one that did the most hospital models
of our partner hospitals thought this was.
They thought this was the correct label for our x-ray scan.
So now if we were to take our counts equals np.bincount labels,
minlength equals 10, look at counts,
and indeed we find that label number nine is the one that has the most counts.
Now, let's go back to our intuitive understanding of differential privacy and say,
okay, differential privacy, this was about computing functions on private datasets,
and our definition of perfect privacy was something like if I
can remove anyone from the input to my database,
I'll think of anyone for my database,
and my query to that database does not change,
then this query has perfect privacy.
Because the output of my query is not conditioned on any specific person.
So how does it apply to this example right here?
The way that applies to this example right here is that instead of saying an individual,
we're going to say a hospital.
If I could remove any hospital from my search for the max,
my arg max function.
So this is my query.
I used the result, query result.
If I could remove any one of these hospitals from this query result,
and the query result would be identical,
then we would say, "Perfect privacy." How great is that?
However, the degree to which we can do this
is actually somewhat conditioned on what the labels actually were.
So if all the hospitals agree,
if every single hospital said,
"It's labeled nine for sure," then we have very low sensitivity.
So we know that we can remove any one of these data points,
and the queries ought to be the same.
More importantly, we know that we could remove any person
from the dataset that
created these labels and the output of this query result be the same.
Because remember, this nine represents a whole group of people.
So when we're think about differential privacy and saying, "Hey,
it's not about numbers,
it's not about ids,
it's about people," I could remove a person from
the dataset that generated this nine and
the output of my query wouldn't be the same, sorry would be the same.
How do I know that? Because I know that no matter what happens to this nine,
this nine could become a 2,976,
and the most that this query result would still be a nine.
So if I know that this one,
the output of the query is not conditioned on this particular value,
then I also know that the output of my query is not
conditioned on anything that created this value,
including all of the people in this hospital.
If I know that across all of these guys, then we're saying,
"Man, this is a near perfect query."
This is not leaking
any private information because the output of
this query result is not conditioned at any specific person.
Now there is one core assumption to this.
That is, these unique partitions of the data.
Meaning that the same patient,
the same person was not present at any two of these hospitals.
The reason for that is that in theory, hypothetically, that person,
if they actually participated in the training of all of these models,
and they were removed in theory, hypothetically,
it's possible that they could actually change the result of all of
these models because the models will have learned something
slightly different such that this output query result was different.
So that's why the core assumption of
PATE is that when you partition your dataset into these partitions,
then you know where the references to people are
that you're trying to protect. Does that make sense?
So ultimately, at the end of the day,
what we're trying to say is the output of this query is immune to
any specific person being
removed from all of the data that was used to create this query.
If we note these partitions are across people,
then we can use the removal of a whole hospitals with the data as a proxy,
as a proxy for moving one person.
The cool thing is that under some conditions,
we can know for a fact that
removing any one of these hospitals from
our calculation wouldn't change the output of the result.
Now, what does all this have to do with epsilon?
How do we actually tie this back to epsilon?
Previous mechanisms that we looked at,
in our previous calculation to differential privacy,
we weren't actually looking at the data,
like we sort of talked about the idea that that's not what you would actually do.
Well, the cool thing about PATE,
the PATE analysis is that they actually figured out
a way to take a pick at these labels and say,
"Hey, how much do these hospitals really agree or disagree?"
Because if they all agree,
I know that my epsilon level is really, really low.
It's only if they disagree that
removing a hospital would actually cause my queries all to be different.
Okay. The PATE analysis is a formal set of mechanisms that's capable of
doing this and actually computing
an Epsilon level that is conditioned on this level of agreement.
So we're going to go ahead and use a tool that has implemented
this analysis to actually do this.
Okay. So this tool is in a toolkit called PySyft.
If you don't have it, go pip install syft and it should import all your dependencies.
I already have it installed, so I'm not going to worry about that.
So then we go from syft.frameworks.torch.differential_privacy,
import pate, pate.perform_analysis.
Okay. So what I'm going to do
next is I'm going to actually generate a synthetic dataset again.
So I've got one pull up over here.
I'm just going to drop it in.
This is a similar style of dataset that we had before,
so num_teachers, num_examples, num_labels.
We generate some preds, we generate some true_indices.
This is what the actual labels should be, this is the labels.
Yeah. We're going to perform our analysis of this.
So these indices aren't necessarily true but they're the ones that came from up here,
perform_analysis, and we're going to say that the teacher_preds equals preds.
I'm going to say that true_indices equals indices.
We're going to say that noise_epsilon.
So this noise_epsilon level is the Epsilon level that we used when noising our examples.
All right. So 0.1 Delta.
So we got to pick it at a level of Deltas from, remember,
Epsilon and Delta, 1e negative 5.
So this is 10 to the power of negative five.
Cool. Now, if we perform this analysis,
it returns two things.
So the first is a data_dependent_epsilon.
So this is the fancy one.
This is the one we're actually looks inside and says,
"Hey, how much agreement is here?"
Tries to give us sort of the tightest Epsilon that it can,
and this is the data_independent_epsilon which is looser.
It's a simpler Epsilon.
It doesn't actually look at the data to be able to tell.
As you can see, data_independent_epsilon.
As you can see, they're very, very, very close to each other.
However, the data_independent one is slightly higher.
So this says there is a teeny, teeny,
teeny, nine amount of agreement between the models.
It's not surprising that there wasn't much agreement.
After all, we randomly generated them.
So now, what are we going to do now?
What I'd like to do is just give you an intuition and show you that if we were to force,
if we were to change these predictions and actually
make it so that there was a certain amount of agreement,
say if the first five examples all 10 hospitals agreed
that it was label 0, this would change.
Let's check it out. Let's rerun it again.
I have forced the first five examples,
so all have perfect consensus at zero.
Now, the data_dependent_epsilon says,
"This dataset only leaks eight Epsilon as opposed
to the 11.7 Epsilon that we would have had to leak before."
So what if we force it to be the first 50?
So we only had a 100 examples,
so I'm getting pretty aggressive here.
Well, then now we get down to 1.52.
So significantly better privacy leak there.
Now, there is one thing that is here.
So we sort of introduce an extreme amount of agreement here,
and so we sort of push the bounds.
This actually tracks the number of moments.
It's a moment tracking algorithm.
So in reality, we would follow
these instructions and we would set these moments by default and set to eight.
So maybe we set this to 20 or something like that.
But the idea here and the intuition here is that the greater the agreement,
the more the predictions agree with each other,
the tighter an Epsilon value we can get.
So intuitively, when you're using PATE,
also this has really strong intuition,
this means that if you can do things with your algorithm to
encourage models at different locations to agree with each other,
to find the true signal,
to not overfit to the data,
that when you actually combine these together later,
you're going to find that you have a less privacy leakage
because each model was better at only memorizing,
only learning the generic information it was going for.
For example, what do tumors look like in humans as opposed
to whether image 576 has a tumor?
So this PATE framework actually rewards you for creating
good generalized models that don't memorize
the data by giving you a better Epsilon levels at the end.
So I hope that you found this to be quite a compelling framework.
Now note also that even though we've used
this sort of healthcare example as like a driving example,
it doesn't have to be datasets that are required from some of the hospital.
If you have a private dataset and a public dataset,
you can leverage labels in the private dataset, split it.
Split the dataset in the 10 or 100 partitions, train your models,
train your future models, and then use that to
annotate your public dataset you can train a model from.
You don't have to be bringing in data from part organizations,
you can do all this yourself.
In fact, in the later project,
we're actually going to do that.
So yeah. I hope you've enjoyed this lesson and I'll see you in the next one.