Before moving on to a description of the final project for this section,
I first wanted to just take a quick pit stop and talk about
where to go from here to continue your education on differential privacy
so that the first and most resounding recommendation that I can give right now is to
read the Algorithmic Foundations of Differential Privacy by Cynthia Dwork and Aaron Roth.
This is the comprehensive book on the subject.
I hope that this video series is actually giving you a really great foundation,
an intuition and encode examples to be able to work with this book so that the pros are,
I mean, it's the definitive work.
It's free online because
Aaron Roth is actually hosting it for free that people can download.
It has the full field.
I think was written in what, 2013? So it has lots of very modern mechanisms,
some great stories, and great intuitions.
I think the most challenging part of it is once you get into it,
it delves pretty deeply into the math and the formal proofs.
So it might be more challenging and more
dense if you're not used to working with this kind of set notation.
However, it is truly the definitive work on the subject, the comprehensive work.
If you're going to teach a course in differential privacy,
this is the textbook that you want to use,
and so I highly recommend checking this out.
Secondarily, you should certainly check out this paper
called The Deep Learning with Differential Privacy, it had some really,
really great concepts that I think are going to be quite influential,
or actually, are already are quite
influential and will continue to be so within the field of deep learning.
As far as topics that you should learn next.
So if this course was longer,
we would have jumped into the exponential mechanism,
we would've jumped into moments accountant,
which is actually talked about in this paper,
as well as differentially private stochastic gradient descent.
I'm confident before too long with these algorithms will be present
in the existing toolkits for differential privacy.
They should be relatively easy to use.
So at the very least,
you want to become familiar with the interfaces and the
APIs of what these algorithms signify and mean.
Then finally, there's a bit of advice.
So if you're used to doing deep learning,
you're probably used to jumping in with both feet first,
and then maybe asking questions later.
I know that in my own pursuits of deep learning I've been very
aggressive to be getting my hands dirty with these techniques,
and like really going for it.
However, when doing differential privacy,
there are some times small nuanced things that can actually cause you negative exposure.
People can actually get hurt if
private information gets leaked because something wasn't implemented correctly.
This is different from a culture that is most popular in AID phone in
communities where if you train a model and it
gets 99 percent accuracy instead of a 100 percent accuracy,
nine times out of 10,
it's not going to be that big of a deal.
With privacy, it's a bit more like cryptography,
where if you're off by just a little bit sometimes that can actually be
a catastrophic mistake that someone can exploit to then steal lots of information.
So for your actual deployments,
the first thing is I would recommend to stick with public frameworks that
are open-source actively being developed on and lots of people have their eyes on.
Because this is an early field,
there's still proofs that come out that it push against different techniques.
So for example, there's been a paper recently
published talking about how for Laplacian distribution.
So remember we were using Laplacian distributions for a lot in this course.
That if you use a Laplace generating
function that isn't implemented in quite the right way,
there's actually an exploit to leak
more information based on the fact that you're using floating point numbers.
Even if you implemented the algorithm correctly as described in this course,
as describing Cynthia Dwork's books,
there can still be little gotchas in
the actual computer science implementation of these things
just like there can be little gotchas in work around in cryptography.
So writing cryptography libraries can be very challenging.
So all there's to say, if you actually are interested
in implementing this within your own organization,
I highly recommend sticking with
public published code that people are vetting, and people are backing,
that people are doing DevOps on,
because if you tried to roll the whole thing from
scratch yourself it's going to be more challenging,
and it's going to be more likely that you'll
introduce vulnerabilities that you might not know about.
Secondarily, on a more positive note,
join the differential privacy community.
So it's a small book,
quickly growing community of a very interesting folks
at the intersection of some folks going from machine learning background,
some folks come from a statistics background,
some folks come from a cryptography background.
It's a really, really vibrant community,
and I've been very pleasantly,
maybe not surprised, but I deeply enjoy being around people in this community.
They typically have a really strong social bent,
they really are interested in actually making the world a better place.
I really have enjoyed being a part of this community,
I highly recommend doing so yourself.
So you can do this by going to conferences, going to workshops,
obviously join open-mind slack which we'll
talk about I think a little bit the next lesson,
with lots of other people who are interested in differential privacy,
but it's really a vibrant group and I highly recommend it.
Third, don't get too ahead of yourself on deployment.
So again, this is a bit more like the first point.
You've got a solid introduction to the concept differential privacy in this course,
but this is by no means a comprehensive course.
This is not enough to do a production deployment at the moment.
However, this is I think a great introduction to the field of differential privacy,
and ultimately will lead you to the skill sets
necessary for production deployments of these algorithms.
So the other thing to do is to keep track of state of the research.
So there's still research being published.
Many of these algorithms are still debated.
So people still try to make counterpoints or maybe this isn't perfectly
privacy preserving to stay update on literature because it's a fast-paced field,
there's new mechanisms coming all the time.
There's new forms of differential privacy,
new definitions of differential privacy coming out all the time,
and it's really exciting field to be in.
But just be very mindful when you're interested in doing this in
production in the real world of just how new this field is,
how quickly it's changing,
and how new the code bases are as well that are actually implemented in these algorithms.
Now, enough on that let's jump into the final project.