Federated Learning is one of
the most widely deployed techniques in the context of private deep learning.
The term was coined at Google a few years ago by Brenda McMann, et al.
And Google has been pioneering this field ever since.
Federated Learning is a technique for
training machine learning models on data to which we do not have access.
So basically, instead of bringing all the data into one machines in the Cloud,
and training a model,
we're going to bring that model to the data,
train it locally wherever the data lives and
merely upload model updates to a central server.
So there are several use cases here we're Federated Learning is quite interesting,
but the first and probably most famous use case is in the context of mobile phones.
If you're familiar with smart phones,
when you open your texting app,
and the texting app tries to predict the next word that you're about to text,
the machine learning model that actually does that,
if you have an iPhone or Android,
it's actually trained using Federated Learning.
Meaning when you go home at night and you plug in your phone and attach it to Wi-Fi,
every once in a while, it'll actually do a bit of local training on your device,
on your own text messages,
and it will send a new model,
a slightly smarter model up to the Cloud and then later you'll
get an updated aggregation of everyone else's model that also went up to the Cloud,
thus giving you a smarter model.
So the nice thing about this approach is that you are able
to benefit from having this texting model inside
your phone despite the fact that you personally
are not generating enough training data for it to become intelligent.
So you're benefiting from this model becoming smart by
looking at thousands and millions of other phones,
without any of these people having to divulge
the private informations contained in their phone,
and without you having to divulge any private information within your phone.
In the context of Federated Learning,
there are also other applications that are very interesting.
One interesting case is predictive maintenance.
So, for example, if you own a car.
Every several 1,000 miles you have to take it in to get an oil change, right?
We just have this fixed number of miles that we have to do this typically.
But Federated Learning could be used to try to
predict when your car needs to go into maintenance
ahead of time by having a model that actually lives within all cars that are on the road,
studying when they actually start to break down.
So in this particular way,
using various aspects of your climate, how you drive,
the kind of engine you have,
these kinds of predictive models could actually become intelligent in doing this.
The nice thing is that, this wouldn't actually require you to
upload any data from your car to some sort of central server.
In theory, a model just comes down to your car,
it learns how to predict when your car is going to require maintenance and
it uploads that ability to predict.
An update to the model,
backup to the Cloud.
Another interesting use cases is in wearable medical devices.
So you can imagine if you have one of those sort of fancy watches,
or wristbands that's tracking your movement, heart rate,
or perhaps even your sleep cycles or if you maybe you log your diet online,
one of these dialoguing apps,
you can imagine that Federated Learning will allow you to learn
a machine learning model which could help you optimize certain parts of your health,
whether it's your diet for having a better sleep cycle,
or how much you move during the day for accomplishing some sort of wake up.
Again, the nice thing here is that you by yourself are not
actually generating enough training data to be able to train a model like this.
But, if you collaboratively trained as
single machine learning model with thousands or millions of other people,
then everyone can benefit from this machine learning model
without anyone having to upload their data to a central Cloud.
Finally, one of the other widely deployed use cases
of Federated Learning is inside of mobile browsers,
often in the context of ad blocking or an auto-complete.
So, when you go up to your browser and you start to type
some website and it tries to predict what
website it thinks you're trying to refer to, again,
that's another example where Federated Learning has been
used out in the world to allow large groups of
individuals to enjoy the benefits of
ML models without having to upload all of their data to the Cloud.
So I hope these examples give you a sense for
the kind of settings when Federated Learning is useful,
and really a context for the setup that
leads to people wanting to use Federated Learning.
The general challenge is that you have a scenario where
a dataset is distributed amongst a large number of sources,
usually because it's being produced by the sources,
in the context of phone's,
browser, wearable medical devices,
or automobiles, for example.
What we want to do is, we want be able to train a machine learning model on that dataset.
But you aren't able to aggregate that data set for a variety of reasons.
Sometimes it's for privacy, right?
There might be a legal restriction that prevents
you from aggregating the data to a central server,
medical data for example has a lot of these kinds of legal restrictions.
There might be user discomfort.
So in the case of this ad blocker or autocomplete use case within browsers,
people don't really want to upload
every webpage URL that they're going to to some central server if they don't need to.
Then of course, there are competitive dynamics.
So if you think in the context that predictive maintenance,
automobile companies might not want to upload to
some central server every time one of their automobiles breaks down.
Now, if it's just within one brand,
maybe just Ford or something like that, that'd be great.
But if you can imagine that if Toyota could
see when Honda cars break down because if some central server,
there could be some strange competitive dynamics or
leaks of potentially negative information.
But Federated Learning isn't just about privacy.
Often it's used because of engineering constraints.
As it turns out, Federated Learning can actually be used to reduce the bandwidth cost of
having to upload datasets to the Cloud by
allowing training to happen locally inside of these devices.
So, this is why the contexts of Federated Learning is an incredibly powerful tool.
It's already been widely deployed to some very substantial use cases,
and it's one of the things that's really advancing the fastest
in terms of privacy, preserving technologies.