Next, we're going to be looking at a toolkit,
that will allow us to perform federated learning called PySyft.
PySyft is an extension to the major deep learning toolkits.
In particular, we are going to be looking at its extension to the PyTorch framework,
which will allow you to do the kinds of remote executions
necessary for federated learning in a deep learning context.
As you can imagine, if I'm a central server,
and I'm trying to orchestrate millions of different devices,
training models in the correct way so that I can aggregate all these gradients,
I need a special set of tools because
the nature of standard deep learning toolkits is that they
assume that you have some dataset
locally in some local framework to let you perform operations.
So what we're going to be looking at here is a new set of tools,
that allow us to actually have an interface that is nearly identical to PyTorch,
but allows us to execute commands on remote machines and
coordinate how data is moved amongst different machines.
That's really what's going to form the foundation for us to be able to do
federated learning on actual distributed dataset