Up until this point, we've been learning about
deep learning in the context of privacy by building things from scratch,
and this is a great way to learn.
However, moving forward we're going to start doing things that are quite complex.
So we're going to want to start using software packages that
are a bit more purpose-built for privacy-preserving deep learning.
For that, we're going to look to the OpenMined, open-source community.
This open-source community has built a variety of tools
that are useful for privacy in the context of deep learning,
including tools for Federated Learning,
for Differential Privacy, for Encrypted Computation, and more.
In particular, we're going to look at the package called PySyft.
So, if you scroll down to the bottom,
you can click this Start Contributing button,
and it will take you to the OpenMined GitHub organization.
So you'll see PySyft is here at the top.
This is a library that builds on top of PyTorch and
TensorFlow for encrypted privacy-preserving deep learning.
For our exercises, we're going to be looking at
the extensions that they've made to PyTorch.
Now, the first thing I'd like for you to do,
scroll down and install Syft.
So you see installation should be quite simple.
So, pip install syft,
and this should download the appropriate dependencies
needed for the library as well as the library itself.
The next thing that I'd like for you to do,
is head on over to the Slack.
So you can click that button here on the Read Me,
or you can come back to the main homepage and click this chat on Slack button.
If you follow the form to create an account,
it will ultimately be led to a portal.
It looks a lot like this.
Slack is, if you haven't used it before,
composed of several main components.
So first, there are channels which are group chats or group discussions.
Then, there are direct messages down here.
Now, when you first get here,
what I would like for you to do is go ahead
and introduce yourself in the general discussion.
You will find that lots of other people who are taking the course,
as well as other people who are interested in
privacy-preserving deep learning in general,
always present in this community.
As privacy-preserving deep learning is still a bit of a nascent community,
it's a good idea to get to know other people who are in the field.
Secondly, as we're just now installing PySyft,
I'd like for you to head over to beginner.
Beginner is a great place to ask questions if you're having trouble installing things,
if you having trouble with any of the examples,
if you think you found a bug in the code or a bug and one of the demos,
or if you get stuck on a project.
This place is a friendly place to build,
ask questions no matter how simple or elementary they might be.
If you're interested in knowing how PySyft is actually being developed as we go,
you can see every new code update and change.
Actually gets pushed into this co-channel,
so it's a good channel to watch.
Of course in here, other people introduce
themselves and talk about their backgrounds and what they're interested in,
and why they're interested in privacy-preserving deep learning.
You can get to know other people who are also in this channel.
Now, development discussion for improving PySyft and seeing how
PySyft is changing happens in this #team_pysyft channel,
which you can keep track off if you're interested.
One more thing of note,
in the channel section,
you'll see there are actually a lot of local communities for OpenMined.
So in particular, people like to gather in
various places around the world to have face-to-face meetups.
It's a good idea to go ahead and look and see if your community is listed,
and if it's not, feel free to go ahead and create one.
With that, now we're going to get back to
actually walking through some new tutorials in privacy-preserving deep learning.
So now, what is PySyft?
PySyft is an extension of several deep learning libraries
with new pieces that make it easier to do privacy-preserving deep learning.
Let me show you how to setup PySyft inside of your [inaudible] notebook.
First, we're going to import Torch like we normally would.
We can create normal Torch tensors and use Torch in the normal way.
However, Syft is an extension of Torch.
So if we import Syft as sy,
the next thing we want to do is create a hook.
What this is going to do?
This is going to actually modify PyTorch with new functionality.
So I'm actually going to pass in the reference to the Torch library here.
Behind the scenes, it actually just modified a bunch of PyTorch API,
so that we can do things that we'd like to do with privacy-preserving deep learning.
But you'll notice that the pieces of PyTorch that we're familiar with work as advertised.
In the next lesson, we're going to start jumping into
some of the new functionality that Syft has given us.