The essence of federated learning is the ability to train
models in parallel on a wide number of machines.
In order to do this, we first need the ability to tell
remote machines to execute operations required for deep learning.
Thus, instead of using torch tensors locally,
we're now going to work with pointers to tensors that exist on a different machine.
However, in order to do this,
we first need to know what is an interface to another machine really look like.
Fortunately, Pysyft creates this interface for us through something called a worker.
The first thing we're going to create is called a virtual worker.
What this really does is it just simulates
the interface that we might have to another machine.
Now a worker in the context of Pysyft really is a new kind of primitive.
So whereas PyTorch and TensorFlow are both solely focused around the primitive type,
the core type of a tensor, with Pysyft,
we have tensors that are owned by a variety of different machines,
a variety of different workers.
So these workers form another core primitive of the framework.
Now, workers really quite something simple.
It's just a collection of objects.
In most cases, these objects will be
simple tensors that we are trying to perform operations with,
but sometimes they can be other kinds of objects as well. Let's try it out.
So if I create a little bit of data here,
I can then use the first piece of functionality that PySyft
added to PyTorch and send this data to Bob.
Now, if I look inside of Bob's objects collection,
I see indeed the tensor that I had originally initialized was actually sent to Bob.
But now this begs the question,
what was returned when I sent it?
This is where PySyft power really starts to be shown for the first time.
What was returned to me was a pointer to the remote object.
Now, pointer is actually a kind of tensor and it has the full tensor API at its disposal.
However, instead of actually executing these commands locally like a normal tensor would,
each command is serialized to a simple JSON or tuple format sent
to Bob and then Bob executes it on
our behalf and returns to us a pointer to the new object.
Now, there are few assets on these pointers that are
required in order for this to be doable.
The first one is location. So we go x.location.
We see that this pointer is pointing towards Bob and we
actually go check and see is x.location equal to Bob,
the answer is true.
X has an ID at location and then x has an ID as well.
These two pieces of metadata actually allow x to communicate with Bob.
So whenever you try to perform a command say addition or subtraction using x,
it's going to send a message to self.location and say, "Hey,
Bob, find the tensor that has
this particular ID and execute the command that I would like for you to execute."
There's one more attribute that all tensors and PySyft have which is an owner.
In this case because we are the client,
the owner defaults to be me.
This reveals one other worker which was created without our knowledge.
This was created when we first imported and hooked PySyft into PyTorch.
This is a worker called local worker.
So you see, whenever we actually communicate with a remote machine,
what we're really doing whenever we execute a command regarding acts is we're saying,
"Hey, local worker, contact Bob and tell him to do this."
So there's a connection between local worker and Bob
and any other workers it's sort of learn about each other.
So let's execute one of those commands now.
So if I go x.get,
just to remind you that x is a pointer,
and I will actually get the information back from Bob.
If I go and look in Bob objects,
you'll see that Bob no longer has any tensors anymore.
Because you can see this is
a very powerful interface that allows us to do everything that
PyTorch can normally do but we can execute it on arbitrary remote machines.
We will see that this pointer interface actually allows us to
coordinate large complex protocols such as Federated Learning with ease.
In the next section, what I'd like for you to do is play around with this.
So what I would first like you to do is to extend
this use of send and instead create two workers.
So I want you to create a Bob worker and then Alice worker.
Then, I want you to boost send and get a tensor to both of those workers simultaneously.
So instead of just calling.send you're going to call.send Bob and Alice. All right.
So go ahead and take a shot at that project,
get used to this interface,
get PySyft imported to your system,
and in the next video,
I'll show you how I would execute this program.