In this video, I'm going to show you how to be able to send and
get tensors to multiple workers at a time.
So this is in the same notebook from the last video,
we already have a worker called Bob.
So the first thing we need to do is to create a second worker,
we're going to call them Alice.
New virtual worker, pass on the hook, ID equals Alice.
Let's create some data we want to send.
Now, as I showed you very briefly in the last video,
we'll say x_ptr = x.send (bob, alice).
If we look at x_ptr, we have a new update.
This is called a multi-pointer.
So, a multi-point or is simply just a pointer that points to multiple machines.
It has an object called child,
which is simply a dictionary of the various workers.
Now, we can also go x_pointer.get and it
returns interestingly two objects instead of one.
You see what was contained within inside of
x_pointer in this multi pointer it was actually, two pointer objects.
So when we call dot get it naturally pull both of them back as separate objects.
However, there is another option we can also use.
It as an option for us to have it automatically sum the results,
which will take these two tensors and sum them together.
This is simply a convenience operation which in some contexts is quite nice.
Now, in the next section, we're going to start looking
at more advanced things that we can
do with pointers to remote tensors,
by showing you how to do
simple arithmetic and other various operations that are inside the hydro
JPI on tensors that are not located on the machine that you are on. See you then.