In this lesson, we're going to learn a bit more about
the APIs that pointer tensors offer,
and the full range of functionality they give us when
controlling pointers to tensors on other machines.
The first thing we'd like to do is initialize some data to play with.
So let's say X equals a torch tensor,
and we'll send this to bob and Y equals another torch tensor,
I have the tensor of ones and we'll send this also to bob.
Now, of course, if we were to send one to Bob and another one to Alice,
then we couldn't do any functions that involve both tensors because as you'd imagine,
they wouldn't be on the same machine.
So as you can see here, we have tensor X which is a pointer tensor,
where the pointer is located on the worker called me,
which is the one that's as mentioned previously initialize inside the hook,
and it has an ID of this 873 in big number.
But it's pointing to a tensor on Bob with an ID that starts with 99233,
and Y is quite similar.
The nice thing about these pointers tensors is that,
we can just pretend that they're normal tensors.
So if it goes Z equals X plus Y,
we've returned a pointer to the output of X plus Y is executed on Bob's machine.
We'll go Z equals z.get,
as you can see the output is correct.
So take this one into a five and add it to one to each of the individual values.
Now, if you prefer to use some of torches functions instead of using methods,
you can also go z equals th.add,
and we pass in x and y,
and this generates a pointer to the output again and of course we can go equals
z.get and look at z and we get the same result.
However torches used for more than
just simple operations and it actually has some more advanced protocols,
so if you consider say back propagation.
So if we were to instead create a couple of tensors which had variable send this to Bob,
we can even use this more advanced functionality.
So let's say x equals the.tensor again,
actually let's just copy these guys from here,
but instead we're going to say requires grad equals true, floating-point numbers.
It's now if we go z equals x plus y,
most sum up to a single number,
and then z backwards or call back propagation,
what this would do normally is it will create gradients on x and y.
So if we actually call x back,
we have x itself and we get x.grad,
that's a tensor of once just as it should be.
So as you can see, the full API of Pi towards that our disposal and as much as possible,
the craters of PySyft have tried to make it feel like you're using
normal Pi torch as close as possible to the original API.
So this leads us to the next project.
What I'd like for you to do in this project is leveraged
this API to train a simple linear model.
So you're going to use sort of the backward function,
you're going to use variables,
and you can even use optimizers or things from nn.modules,
so like nn.Linear for example.
So you might be familiar with this module, right?
So and just learn a simple linear model with one core constraint,
I want the data and the model to be located on Bob's machine.
So take a step at this project,
and in the next video,
I'll show you how I would do this with PySyft.