So in this project, we're going to use the pointer API that we've learned about in
the last video and train a simple linear model on a remote worker.
In this case, we're going to train it on Bob's worker.
So first we want to create some training data.
So let's create some toy input data.
Now what I'd like to do here is initialized data that is about as small as possible.
So this is not a real-world size neural network,
but it's going to form the basis for what we
do when learning some of the other techniques
because federated learning and
the different oxidation techniques and
things that we're doing are complicated enough as it is.
So we're going to work with a simple linear model for a lot
of these exercises just to reduce the complexity of everything else was opposed
to using like a big communist and lots of fancy features so that we can really focus
just on the privacy preserving aspects of what we're trying to do.
So we're going to say requires_grad=True, and we're going to send us to Bob.
I'm going to create targets,
and we're just going to learn a real linear relationship
between this column being one and the target.
So now Bob has a data set input target,
both around Bob's machine.
Now the next thing we need are just some linear weights,
and create like this again requires_grad=True and send it to Bob.
All right, so now Bob has our input data,
has a target data, and has a set of weights.
So let's start by just doing a little bit of forward propagation.
So our prediction will just be input matrix multiplied by the weights,
prediction is also a pointer as you might expect the loss
is pred minus target squared to two in the sum.
So this is mean squared error loss. Oops, typo there.
Then we backpropagate, and then we do a weight update.
This is our alpha of 0.1,
then we want to zero out our gradients when we're done.
So that small typo and was your grades at
the end so they don't accumulate over time and then print loss.
Of course we have to actually get the loss so we can see it.
Beautiful. If we do this several times hopefully,
we should see the loss start to go down.
Look at that. Let's do an iterator.
So as you can see,
once we have moved our data and our weights to row machine,
all this code is just using native normal run of the mill PyTorch.
The idea is that for this tool to make it so that things like federated learning and
remote execution is dead simple if you already know how to use PyTorch.
Now, in the next section,
we're going to explore a couple of the "gotchas" and
other things that can be a bit more challenging to sit or understand,
or perhaps debug when you're on
a remote machine or when you're when you have a connection to a remote machine.
So the next lesson, I'll see you there.