So before we continue on to other privacy preserving techniques,
I would like to first talk about garbage collection and a few of
the common errors that people seem to run into
when using PySyft to control tensors on remote machines.
So first, let's talk a little bit about garbage collection
and the life cycle of remote objects.
So if we were to clear all the objects in
Bob just so it's easy to tell when something gets deleted,
so we'll see bob_objects is now empty.
This is the collection of all the objects in Bob.
If we're then to create a tensor and send it to
Bob and then if we were to delete our pointer to this tensor,
so x as you know is our pointer,
shows first just so you can see, Bob's objects is there.
If we were to delete this, what should happen?
Well, PySyft always assumes that when you created the tensor and send it to someone,
you should continue to control the life cycle of that tensor.
Which means if you delete your pointer to the tensor that you created and sent,
the tensor that you're pointing to should also get deleted.
Now, this is controlled by a very specific attribute on each pointer.
Supposed to create another pointer, x.child.garbage_collect_data.
By default, this is set to true when you call.send.
This means, when sort of me the pointer,
when either pointer get garbage collected,
should I send a message to Bob saying,
"Hey, go delete that tensor."
By default, this is set to true.
So if we set this to false,
then this would actually turn garbage collection off at this pointer and it would no
longer send a message to Bob saying that they
should delete tensors when they get removed.
There's an interesting gotcha when working in Jupyter Notebooks.
So normally, know if,
so Bob has this object right now.
If I said x equals asdf and this got garbage collected, Bob would lose it.
So now Bob is empty.
However, Jupyter Notebooks had this thing
where they store every command you've ever executed,
and so occasionally if you do a few commands,
they'll get cached in such a way where
garbage collection will no longer collect those objects.
So you might end up with just things,
just by virtue of the fact you're working in a Jupyter Notebook,
it can keep a couple extra objects around.
So let me show you what I mean specifically.
So if we create another one of these and then we go
x and we'll just call the double under reaper here,
then if I go x equals this or as this,
x equals asdf, there's still a reference to it.
The pointer never actually got garbage collected.
If you go delete x, it still lives on.
But this is not because of some issue with
PySyft or it's just an issue with sort of unknown gotcha.
When you use Jupyter Notebooks,
there are some things that actually end up having another reference
to your object that you have in your Notebook and
thus since this pointer doesn't get deleted.
Since this pointer doesn't get garbage collected,
it never sends an execution or
a command to the remote worker telling it to delete the thing that it's pointing to.
So this happens occasionally. So now we'll go ahead and go erase these again.
So Bob equals bob.clear_objects, bob._objects.
So clear this one more time.
Then I just want to show you that
this garbage collection works for like for loops and stuff too.
So if I were to do for i in range 1000, x equals th.tensor.
So if I were to send this tensor to Bob 1000 times,
bob._objects should still only have one.
The reason for that is every time this for loop went through again,
it reassigned x and deleted the tensor that was
returned from here which caused it to be garbage collected from the remote machine.
Now, why is this important?
The reason this is important is that it means that when you're
doing say federated learning or you're doing the exercise,
the project that we did previously where we were learning a simple linear model,
when we iterate through this for loop and we're generating a new prediction tensor,
a new loss tensor,
and like all the intermediate tensors that go into executing each of these parts,
if we end up deleting our reference to that execution,
then the remote machine will also delete it.
This is like a really good default piece of behavior to have.
Because otherwise, when we ran this for loop,
we would end up generating and persisting thousands of
tensors even when we're doing just simple forward and backpropagation.
So it's just a good thing to know about this particular sort of
garbage collection feature so that you know that when
objects are created or it seem to disappear from
remote workers that they're actually attached to the pointers that are pointing to them.
I know it might seem like a little bit of an advanced thing,
but it's just something you need to know
about as far as what are the core assumptions of how
this API is built before jumping
into too deep into federate learning and into your own sort of custom projects.
Now, there's a couple of other sort of
convenience areas that I wanted to also mention while we're here.
So I see that Bob still have and Bob has this also x equals th.tensor([1,2,3,4,5]).
So let's create x and y, but I'm not going to send y to Bob.
I'm going to try to call a command on both.
So again, x is a pointer to Bob,
why is a data set tensor that I have here?
So if I do this, it returns an error.
PureTorchTensorFoundError, which means that one of these is a regulatory tensor,
one of these is a pointer to one.
If I scroll down to the bottom and say you tried to call a method involving
two tensors where one tensor is actually
located on another machine, it's a pointer tensor.
Call.get on the PointerTensor or.send to Bob on the other tensor.
So this gets populated automatically.
Here are the two tensors that we tried to work with,
and this is really just to try to make it obvious when you accidentally do this.
Another common error that people will do,
so we scroll down here,
is send Alice and two different machines and we'll get a very similarity.
So you try to call add involving two tensors which are not on the same machine.
One tensor is on Bob while the other tensor is on Alice.
Use combination of move, get,
or send to co-locate them to the same machine.
So again, if you see these,
just follow the instructions and hopefully you'll be led to
the right series of operations that you're interested in performing in the first place.
All right. In the next session,
we're going to jump a little bit deeper into privacy preserving
deep learning techniques using these core primitives. See you then.