In this lesson, we're going to build what we just learned about in Pi sift
and train our first federated learning model.
Now, that's going to be about as simple as it can get.
What we're going to do is, we're going to just distribute
a tiny toy data set across two different workers,
and then we're going to show and learn how we can
train a model while the data stays on those workers.
First what we want to do is we want to create
a simple model that can learn from some data.
Then we'll look at the processes that we
want to take to be able to train it using federated learning.
So let's start. So we'll create some data.
Say, I've got some data code here.
So this data code is just,
this should look very familiar, we used it above.
It's got two inputs and one output for each example
and we're going to train a simple linear model like we did a few lessons back.
So we need to have in it. So from torch import nn.
I think really the optimizer too.
There we go. So we have a simple linear model.
So what's the first thing we're going to do is?
We want to create our optimizers.
So stochastic gradient ascent.
Params equals model dot.
This is just normal PyTorch code, right?
The first thing that we need to do in our loop is
zero out our gradients. Then, let's make a prediction.
So predict equals model data, beautiful.
We want to calculate the loss function.
So we can do is explicitly.
So we're going to use mean squared error loss here.
I propagate that. Take a step to our optimizer.
Then let's just print the loss. Cool perfect.
All right, so now if we did this multiple times,
we should see this loss go down.
So we'll say, 20 iterations.
Actually that's because of variable,
and we'll have a train method. There we have it.
A simple linear model that can learn on some toy data.
So how do we make this federated?
Well, the first thing we need to do is set up our example.
So right now all of our data is with us.
So you might imagine that our data is in the cloud,
we're on the centralized machine right now.
So when we think about this code,
we think about what we are allowed to access, what we're allowed to use.
Kind of view ourselves internally and our mind as the central server.
What we would like to do is actually move this data off
to individual machines somewhere else that are owned by
other people so that we can then go through the exercise of trying to train
a model that's doing training on those machines.
The first thing to do is split our data into
different pieces and then send it to two different workers.
I believe we still have Bob and Alice from these examples.
Bob and Alice, perfect.
So let's take our data and make data Bob
which is the first two rows, and we'll send it to Bob.
Target Bob will be the first two rows of data again and we'll send it to Bob.
So those are collated with Bob,
co-located with Bob rather.
We'll have data Alice equals data,
we'll send it to Alice.
Realize this should be target, perfect.
All right, now let's take these and put these in a list of tuples.
So we'll say data sets equals,
and then our first one is Bob.
So data, Bob, target Bob.
Then our second one can be data Alice, target Alice.
Now, I want to use the same model and we're going to use the same optimizer.
Perfect. So again, most of this is still very familiar PyTorch code.
The only thing that's different is just the fact that now we
distributed our data set across Bob and Alice's machines.
So the first half of our data set is on Bob's machine and
the second half of our data set is on Alice's machine.
So in our for loop, previously,
we iterated over every example and we basically trained on the whole data set.
This one batch.
We trained in the whole thing, every time step.
But now, we have an extra for loop where we iterate over
each individual person in our example.
So let's see here.
So let's just say that we have one example.
So we'll say, target data.
Target equals data sets zeros.
This is the first data set.
If we look at data, it is a pointer.
So that's appointed tensor and the ID of the pointer is this number,
the idea to pointer on Bob's machine.
So this is a pointer to this tensor that's located on Bob's machine.
So before we really get started here, we have an issue.
So our model is located here or as our data is located on Bob's machine.
So the first thing we need to do is say, model equals models.senddata.location.
So if you remember,
when we talked about pointers,
each pointer has a reference to the worker,
the virtual worker that exists on the other machine.
In this case, we're dealing with virtual workers.
This actually is the workers,
this is the Python object that we interact with.
In the case of this being a pointer to another machine,
this is a client that basically knows how to send messages to the other worker.
But for all intents and purposes,
we can just treat this as the worker. So what does this line do?
This line iterates through every tensor inside this model.
So in this case, it's a weights tensor in a bias tensor,
because linear model has two tensors.
So in basically, every tensor in model.parameter.
So both of these tensors.
It's going to call dot send in place on all those tensors.
So if I run this and then look at the parameters again,
as you can see now, they're all pointers to data that is elsewhere.
So the nice thing here is that this convenience function that allows us to say,
hey take this model and send it to wherever the data happens to be located.
So that's going to be our second step.
Now the next thing that we can do is same steps that we did before.
So we'll call zero grad and optimizer,
which was zero at the gradients.
Pred equals model data.
So this makes it prediction.
Use the wrong handle there. There we go.
Again, actually, this was a useful error.
So this was the error.
This is the wrong image now because I passed in the wrong tensor.
So underscore data, which is from right here and then we're going to say
loss equals pred minus target squared and take the sum.
I did it again. Silly me.
Lost.backward. Again, all this is being executed on the remote machine and then opt.step.
One last thing which brings the model back to us.
So now, the first thing that we do.
Send the model to the remote worker,
send the model to the data.
This is the federated part.
Do normal training. Get smarter model back.
As you can see, we can train in this way.
However, the even nicer thing is that now we can iterate through this data sets
object and our model will send in train at all the locations that the data is located in.
Pretty cool, huh? So now, we wrap this into an outer iterator. There we go.
Now, our model trains across a distributed data set.
Now this is a very small change.
Thanks to the convenience of the PySyft library
most of our code still looks like normal PyTorch code,
and we have a full flexibility of the PyTorch API at our disposal.
The only thing that we really needed to change was where
the model was located when we were performing federated learning.
Now, this takes an important step towards preserving the privacy of our users.
However, there are still a couple of issues with this particular example.
When we go into the next examples in the next lessons,
they're really going to be focusing on how we can further alleviate
and further preserve the privacy of the individuals who are involved.
So the first one is this.
So if you think about this model being sent,
trained on one example and then we're getting it back,
if I look at the diff between these two models,
it's quite possible that I could really reverse engineer quite a bit of information about
what this data actually does or what the data actually is on the other machine.
So for example, if you're familiar with word embeddings.
So often a neural net will have word embeddings.
Maybe it's a sentiment classifier or
you're training a word to vec model or something like this.
If say I send the model to Bob,
Bob performed one batch of training on a tweet.
For example, maybe the tweet said,
"I like purple peanuts."
Then, Bob sent them all back to me after having only trained on that one tweet.
Well, I could look inside my word embeddings and I can say,
"Hey, which embeddings actually changed?
Which embeddings did Bob modify?"
What that would end up telling me is that
the only embeddings that Bob actually modified were,
"I like purple and peanuts."
This would allow me to basically reverse engineer Bob's data by just
looking at the difference between the model that I send and the model that I got back.
Now, there are two main ways that we mitigate this.
The first one is that we just train more than one iteration.
So when we train over and over and over again,
we train with a large amount of data on Bob's machine like this
further gives Bob a certain degree of privacy because it becomes
more difficult to reverse engineer what the gradients,
where as Bob works with more data.
So in the case of the word embeddings example,
if Bob actually modifies every word embedding because he trains
on all of the English Wikipedia when I sent the model to him,
then it would be much more difficult to know exactly what it said.
But this is again still a bit of a hand-wave issue.
It's not really solving the problem of
guaranteeing that we can't reverse engineer something from from Bob's data.
So the next strategy that we employ is that instead
of bringing the model directly back to us and then sending it to Alice,
we instead train multiple different models in parallel on different workers,
on different people's data sets.
So that then we can average those models together and the only model that we see,
the only model that we get back to us is an average of multiple people's models.
If you've already taken the differential privacy section of this course,
then you'll be familiar with the concept that when we average information,
when we take sums of information across multiple different people,
then we begin to be able to create
plausible deniability as to who actually modified each weight.
This matters here.
So for example to go back to the word embedding example,
let's say that I was training on a Twitter corpus across a 100 different people.
So I sent a copy of the model to
a 100 different people and each of them trained a few 1,000 tweets on the local machine.
Then I get back a model and I can see all the different word embeddings that are
modified and someone modified the word password.
The trouble is that because the model has already been averaged,
I don't know which person
actually touched the word embedding password. Could have been multiple people.
Could have been just one person.
It's tough for me to know.
If you remember the definitions that we have previously about epsilon and delta,
then if we add a little bit of noise after the aggregation,
then we can further protect the privacy of
individuals such that maybe no one touched the password,
and this is actually just a little bit of the noise that was
added to the model during the aggregation process.
So as you can see,
this is really where we start to cross over from
just pure remote execution back into
some of the concepts and the core concepts around privacy
that we learned about in the differential privacy section.
But first, before we get to all this,
we're going to figure out how we can train
a model on multiple different workers at the same time
and secondly how can we properly perform the great aggregations,
and then really building out the tools that we're going to need for this and
the extensions of PySyft that we're going to need to know about to use this.
So we're going to unpack in the next section. See you there.