In this lesson, we're going to learn how to orchestrate
the movement of data between multiple different workers directly.
In order to do this, we're going to realize that we can actually
extend the pointer framework that we were using to
manipulate remote data and actually have pointers to pointers to data.
Let me show you what I mean. First, let's take
our Bob and Alice workers and clear out all the objects on them.
So let's just simply delete all the tensors that happen to be on
Bob and Alice that might be around from previous exercises,
and then let's create some data that we can then start to work with.
So let's say, x equals to th.tensor ([1,2,3,4,5]).
So this is just a normal tensor so as we've been working with before.
So the first thing, let's take this and let's send this to Bob.
So now I've got a pointer to it and Bob has this object,
but now we're going to do something else.
We're going to say x.send(alice).
What this does actually sends this pointer to
Alice and replaces x on our machine with a pointer to that pointer.
So now, if we look at bob._objects,
well, that data hasn't actually moved.
But if we go alice._objects,
now we see that on Alice's machine,
Alice has a pointer from Alice to Bob and
our pointer no longer points to Bob instead it points to Alice.
So whenever we were to send a message to
contact this tensor to use it to add two tensor together or subtract,
the message would first go to Alice's machine,
wait to be processed there,
which would call this pointer.
Then this pointer will then forward that message to Bob's machine,
where it would actually be executed up here.
Let's see an example of that.
There it was. So now, we have a new pointer.
This again still pointing to Alice's machine.
If we look inside of bob._objects,
we see that now there are two tensors on Bob's machine.
If we look at alice._objects,
we see two tensors as well;
however this time, both of them are pointers.
So the interesting thing to note here is that the new pointer that was
created or the new tensor that was created has the exact same pointer chain,
same dependency chain, same ownership chain as
the original tensor that was used to create it.
So when we said y equals x plus x,
x has a certain dependency chain.
So x is owned, you can think of,
by both Alice and Bob to the extent that we as
the central server cannot actually contact that tensor.
We can't use that tensor,
we can't do anything to that tensor unless both Bob and Alice allow us to.
Because we could send a message to Alice and Alice would say, "Uh-uh,
I'm not forwarding this to Bob because I don't want to," for a various reasons.
Maybe it's privacy or just doesn't want
to or doesn't know where Bob is anymore, who knows what.
But alternatively, Bob could also say,
"No, I'm not going to allow you to perform this operation."
So in a sense,
both Alice and Bob are actually joint owners over this one digital asset.
Now this also leads to the second internal conclusion where if we were to try
to say do an operation between two tensors that we do not have the same chain structure,
it would lead to an error.
So let's say let's create this tensor chain again.
Let's have another one called y.
So we've sent this to Alice.
Send to Jon.
Do we have a third worker?
Let's pick a word called Jon.
There we go. Z equals x plus y.
As you can see, because this was using tensors where the actual data,
the data is on Bob's machine, that's where we sent it.
So the data is in the right location.
But because Jon and Alice disagree,
they don't have the same ownership structure along the way,
this can trigger an error.
Now the next thing is,
how do we get this data back?
Well, since we have a pointer to Alice's machine,
if we call.get,
then we actually get the pointer from
Alice and now we're pointing directly to the data again.
So let me actually show you that this actually removed the object from Alice's machine.
So let's clear these objects and reset
up this experiment so it's clean so that we can see it.
I don't actually need this other tensor for it now either.
Okay. So now Bob and Alice each have a tensor.
Alice has a pointer tensor,
Bob has the actual data.
So now if I call x.get and we look at this again,
Bob still has the actual data but
Alice no longer has the pointer because she sent it to us,
and now we are pointing directly at Bob's data.
So then if I were to call x.get again,
it would actually get the data back,
and now Bob has no data.
Beautiful. So I hope this interface really feels intuitive to you.
We tried to make this as simple, and easy,
and natural for the average PyTorch user as
possible and all the things that you should have expect to work indeed worked.
The other thing that I think you should take away from this is that,
pointers are actually first-classes.
It's like they R tensors for all intensive purposes; they have IDs.
So you could do a pointer chain here that is 50-people long if you wanted to,
and it would pass all the messages along as you specified it.
Even, actually, so one thing I didn't cover yet was a garbage collection.
So let's say if I create this tensor,
so on Bob and Alice machine and I go delete
x then we look at Bob and Alice machine again,
as you can see, garbage collection collected the whole chain.
Because it assumed that since we deleted the pointer,
that it should delete the thing that we're pointing to.
When we delete that pointer,
then it should delete the thing that that was pointing to.
So the nice thing here is that again
just like with the other tools we worked with with before,
we can do federate learning or other complicated algorithms,
and in theory the default behavior for
how objects are collected will prevent memory leaks
and memory explosions from objects getting so just left around.
Yeah. So that's this nice tool,
and what we're going to be able to see in the next lesson is how we can use
these pointer chains to actually orchestrate how data moves amongst a group of workers.
So instead of just calling send and get,
we're going to be able to actually move data around directly like telling Bob,
"Hey, send this data not to me and then I'll send it to someone.
Send it directly to Alice," for example.
So in the next lesson, we'll jump into that. I'll see you there.