In this video, we're going to learn how we can use pointer chains to
orchestrate the movement of data directly between remote workers.
So the first thing we want to do is clear the objects in Bob and Alice's workers.
This will just make it easy for us to see what's going on.
Awesome. Let's create some data and send it to Bob and Alice.
Specifically, we're going to send the data to
Bob and I'm going to send a pointer to that data to Alice.
Beautiful. So the command
that we're going to learn how to use in this video is called remote_get.
It goes like this. So this is an inline command.
Instead of calling get directly and pulling say this pointer up to us,
up to the local worker,
this is actually going to go down to this pointer and call get on this pointer,
which just going to pull the data from Bob to Alice.
So if I call remote_get, notice x is still the same wrapper.
So it's still pointing to Alice,
but now Bob doesn't have any data at
all and the data itself has moved to Alice. All right.
So when we call this remote_get. It was as if we were telling Alice say, "Hey, Alice,
call that get on your pointer and pull the data that Bob has to Alice's machine."
So we were able to orchestrate this data to
move from Bob's to Alice's machine without ever touching our machine.
This forms the basis for how we can continue to orchestrate
increasingly complex protocols involving larger numbers of workers.
Now as it turns out,
we don't necessarily have to actually create this
whole double send and then remote_get business,
we also have the convenience operator for doing this ourselves.
So right now, let's say that the data is on Alice's machine.
If we want it to move back to Bob,
we can go x.move(bob) and
then our pointer becomes appointed to Bob instead of being appointed to Alice.
So now appointed to Bob and Bob has the data again.
Alice, this is a garbage collection issue.
This is because we still have a pointer to it.
So let me clean up here so you can actually see this.
So I'm going to send this to Bob.
As you can see,
Alice does not have anything yet.
x.move(alice), and now Bob
doesn't have anything and Alice does.
So we have to orchestrate this movement of data
directly from one worker to another using the move function.
Under the hood inside the move function,
it actually first sends the pointer down to
the machine you want to move the data to and then calls remote_get.
So it just uses the same protocol and move as a convenience operator.
Now, in the next video,
we're going to talk a bit more about the project that I'd like to use these tools
that you've learned so far in the context of Federated Learning. See you then.