Now this brings us to your final project for course two.
Your final project is to do Federated Learning,
where the central server is not trusted with the raw gradients.
In this final project notebook,
you'll receive a data set,
and I want you to train on the data set using Federated Learning.
However, the gradients should not come up to the central server in raw form.
Instead, you should use this new.move for command,
to move all of the gradients to one of the workers,
sum them up there,
and then bring that batch up to the central server.
The idea here is that the central server never
actually sees the raw gradient for any person.
Now you might be asking yourself, "Wait,
but that means one of the workers sees the rock gradients."
Well, we'll get to that in course three
when we look at various forms of secure aggregation.
But for now, I want you to,
in this last project,
do a larger-scale Federated Learning case
where you handle the gradients in a special way.
Good luck, and I'll see you in the next course.