In the previous course,
we had federated learning where we designed a new way for our gradient to be aggregated.
In particular, in the last project,
you were able to use the end get and send functionality to make it so that
individual data owners could send gradients
directly to each other before sending it up to the module owner.
While this was certainly a nice feature,
in the real world,
we would like to be able to choose arbitrary individual,
someone totally separate from this situation,
to be able to perform the gradient aggregation.
So this brings us to our first lesson of this course,
where we can use the same technology,
the same API from last lesson to instead have a trusted aggregator.
In theory, this is a neutral third party who has a machine
that we can trust to not look at the gradients when performing the aggregation.
This is advantageous over the last setup because instead of having
to trust one of the data owner to perform aggregation,
who is plausibly sympathetic to the privacy desires of the other data owners,
but could still be malicious.
Allowing a third neutral party means that,
we can choose anyone on the planet,
meaning that we have a much larger pool to search for in terms of looking for
trustworthy people and the likelihood that we
can find the trust with the person is much higher.
So next I would like for you to take this on yourself.
For our first project,
I'd like for you to modify the project you've finished in the last module
and instead have a trusted secure aggregator,
third party, perform the gradient aggregation,
instead of having the data owners do it themselves.
You can perform this on any arbitrary data set or model,
it need not be large or complex.
You need only demonstrate that,
the neutral third party performs the gradient aggregation.