In this section, we're going to learn how to view
federated learning with a trusted aggregator,
which means that when we actually aggregate our gradients from multiple workers,
instead of bringing them to a central server to aggregate them,
or having them send gradients directly to each other.
We're going to have everyone who's involved in the federated learning process or
the federated learning session send all of their gradients to a neutral third party,
which we're going to call a secure worker.
So first, let's set up PySyft.
So we're going to do all the normal things we did before.
So, import syft, import torch,
hook torch, and then import a few other things from torch.
Then let's create a few workers.
So in this case, we're going to create three workers;
Bob, Alice, and secure worker.
So Bob and Alice are going to be our data owners,
and secure worker is going to be this trusted third party
that is able to perform that good aggregation.
Now, we're doing this additional step which
for virtual workers is not strictly speaking necessary,
however, for workers in a real-world,
if you're going to use socket workers and some of
these other HTTP worker is you actually do need to do this.
You do inform workers that other workers exist.
So we have Bob, Alice and secure worker,
we're just letting them know that the address is.
We have a reference to these other workers.
So now we're going to have use the same toy data set that we used in the last example,
and we're going to train the same simple linear model
just to keep everything pretty simple.
So that's our data and target.
Here's Bob's data, so we'll set it to Bob.
Here's Alice's data, which we'll send to Alice.
Then we'll initialize a toy model to be the same model that we were working with before.
So now, we're all set up.
So we've got our model and our central server.
You've got a data set that's distributed,
and now let's start working on federated learning.
So the first thing we're going to do it's a little bit different this time.
Is that instead of just having one model that we
send to and from each individual person in synchrony.
We actually want to have two different models that we
send to each of the workers because we want that to be averaged.
So we have Bob's model which equals model.copy and we're going to send it to Bob.
We're going to have Alice's model, which is a copy of the original model,
and we're going to send it to Alice.
This also means that we need to have two separate optimizers.
So we'd have one for the parameters Bob's model and one for the parameters of Alice's.
So Bob's optimizer equals optim.
So this is just standard by torch stuff.
Sgd params equals bobs_model.parameters, parameter equals 0.1.
Then Alice's optimizer equals optim.
SG descent params Alice's_ model.parameters, parameter equals 0.01.
Great. Now, let's do a step of training for Bob's model.
So first thing we'll do is bobs_opt.zero_grad,
so zero out the gradients.
bobs_pred is just going to be bobs_model, bobs_data.
As you can see, this is all working with the pointers as it should, bobs_loss.
Then we're back propagating.
Beautiful. Now, we want to do bobs_opt.step.
So the weight update and then we'll just get bobs_loss right now.
So my O key
is not doing what it's supposed to.
That is super odd. Okay. Well, I'm going to just copy that for now.
All right.
Okay.
There we go.
If we do this multiple times,
we can see that Bob's loss goes down.
So now I also want to do this separately for Alice.
We can just replace all references to Bob to the references to Alice.
Make sure I don't miss any here.
Like it might have been plural.
All right. It seems to learn. So now
we've got this ability to train Bob's analysis workers.
But then, we come to the question
of how are we going to average these two models together.
So we have Bob's model, we have Alice's model.
We trained both of them separately on these different machines.
But now I want to be able to average them together.
Well, we have this nice convenience method or we can go alices _model.move secure_worker.
What this does and it's similar
to.send that you might have used previously on the worker.
So it just iterates through
every parameter analysis model and calls.move on that parameter inline.
So now, we can do bobs_model.moves secure_worker.
Now, both Bob and Alice's model are on secure_workers.
So if we look at secure_worker._objects we can
see here all the parameters for Bob's analysis model.
Now, all we need to do is just average them together.
So if you have alices_model.weight.data plus bobs_model.weight.data.
I'm going to average them, so we'll divide them by two.
Then we'll call it.get.
then we'll say, model,
which is our global model,.weight.data.set to read this, boom.
Now, we just averaged our weights,
and then we'll do the same thing for bias.
So these are the two parameters that we have in linear model.
Now, we have just average our models and brought them back up,
brought just the average version of the model backup to the central secure server.
So now all we really need to do is just put this whole thing in a
big for loop so that we can rinse and repeat.
So let's see here.
We can take this, and this,
and this, and then we move it. We average it.
So we'll call this for num_rounds in, for round_iter.
So at one session of this is called a round. So that could enable iter.
This is the number of iterations in the round.
We can actually print Bob and Alice's last loss.
There you have it. Federated learning where
the gradient aggregation happens on a neutral third party.
So it just makes it so that each sort of layer of additional functionality adds
a little bit more privacy and a little more flexibility
to the different scenarios that we can use federated learning in.
So in this case, now we are flexible enough to be able to
do federated learning where we work with a secure worker,
a third third-party aggregator.
Actually this kind of setup is actually the most popular one.
So in several large-scale deployments,
actually use a trusted machine that is trusted to aggregate weights together,
and then delete what it has leftover.
We didn't put the delete part in here,
but we could certainly do that if we did secure_worker.clear_objects. There you go.
Now as your worker reliably got rid
of all of the tensors that have had stored on this machine.
So there you go. I hope you've enjoyed this project.
In the next section, we're going to build on this a little bit more