Now there's one additional trick that we need to add to
make the protocol truly secure.
The issue here with this over simplified protocol is that,
when we split Bob's X into a two and a three,
because we're decrypting through a simple addition,
if we assume that we're using positive numbers for our shares,
then Bob actually knows a little bit about the shared number when receiving his share.
That is, that the shared number is at least greater than two.
It's not a lot of leaked information,
but it's a little bit.
It's something we can simply address by modifying our protocol just slightly.
That is the decryption process which will actually be shares summed together,
modulus as some number Q.
Typically a very large prime number.
What this means that,
there is now an infinite number of shares,
that Bob could have,
that would mark the same alpha value.
So we can actually see in this example,
Bob share is quite large and Alice's share is also quite large.
But the decryption is actually still just a simple five.
So with this protocol,
the addition that we saw before still works,
but we get this final added protection.