So in this next project,
I'd like if you to take the raw protocol you just learned
about and create several functions which are implemented.
First, create a method called encrypt which accepts two input parameters,
the number to be encrypted,
and the number of shares to be split into,
and returns a tuple of shares.
Second, create a method called decrypt which
accepts as input a tuple of shares and returns the decrypted value.
Finally, create a method called add which accepts two tuples of shares and returns
a single tuple shares which are added correctly
according to the protocol specified in the previous concept.
Good luck, and I'll see you in the next concept.