So in this video I'm going to show you how I would create these different methods,
which can implement this additive secret sharing protocol.
So the first thing that we want to be able to do was,
define an encrypt method.
So we had a requirement for this where the encrypt method except the tuple,
we're going to call it x, and then a number of shares that it should create.
We're going to set that to be default to three.
Now, as you move from the protocol,
encryption is really about generating three shares such
that when we sum them together and take a modulus of that sum,
modulus, some large prime,
that it will decrypt to the correct value.
So the first thing we're going to do is outside of the actual method,
is populate a list of shares.
So as an empty list, we're going to put
our shares and the first thing I can do is actually,
under the assumption that we are generating three shares,
I can generate the first two shares, totally randomly.
Then it is just about figuring out what to set the third share value two,
so that their sum, actually sum to the appropriate number, modulus Q.
Now, first thing we're going to do is,
choose a really large Q as well.
It'd be a nice thing to have here,
we can use this big number here,
and then I go for I in range,
in share, minus one, shares.append, random per randint, zero to Q.
The idea here is that, again,
the values of the first two shares don't matter because the only constraint that we have,
is that, the all three shares, must sum to something.
So once we have the first two shares,
we can then use those to calculate what the third share should be.
For that, the final share,
is just going to be the sum of these shares mod Q,
and then we're going to subtract this from Q,
which is the difference between,
when this wraps around,
which is Q and the sum of these values thus far.
So this is the distance between when this would basically revert back to zero.
Then we do plus x plus whatever our value is and I believe,
let's set x to be five for now.
The shares append the final share,
and now we have our final shares.
So now if I were to just say sum,
these shares, log Q,
we get out five.
Perfect, it is exactly what we were trying to do.
So this is actually our encrypt method.
I did say I wanted to return a tuple,
so we can do tuple,
and cast this to be a tuple.
So now if I say, encrypt, number five,
I said in shares, equals 10.
That didn't work because we're setting this right here.
Perfect. All right. So now,
we have the ability to encrypt a number using additive sharing.
Okay. Now, let's work on a decrypt method.
So a decrypt method is just going to accept shares as input
and then return the sum of these shares, mod Q.
Easy-peasy.
Now, in some cases, in some language,
you have to worry about say overflow issue here,
where you'd need to actually, mod Q as you're summing up the shares,
but this particular case Q isn't that large, so it's not too big of a deal.
In Python, it's actually pretty good at managing really large numbers.
It's got lots of conveyance items that are put.
So now, if I say, decrypt,
encrypt, five, boom, decrease back to five. Pretty cool.
All right and then the last method we need to do was an add.
For that, it accepts two different tuples.
Now, you remember, the addition is really just
about adding the corresponding shares together.
So in this case, this is as simple as,
just iterating through each share [inaudible] together.
So for I in range, length of a,
I guess we could assert then a equals len b,
c.append ai plus bi,
mod Q, return tuple c. All right.
So now, if we said, decrypt,
add encrypt five, encrypt 10, made a mistake.
Wrong bracket. Supposed to be parentheses.
Actually, I think we've said one too many.
Boom, there we go.
So now, we can do encrypted addition between
two numbers that are encrypted into multiple shares.
So I guess just to break this apart, the more explicitly.
So you can see what these look like,
just say there are definitely,
generating shares into the hood.
Notice every time we do this, it actually generates a different set of shares
because they're randomly generated. How about that?
But they always do get to the same value.
So I hope you've enjoyed this project, and to the next section,
we're going to build on this and learn a bit more about the types of
things we want to do with this encrypted computation. See you then.