So as you know,
our goal is to aggregate gradients in the context of
federated learning using additive secret sharing technique,
specifically the additive secret sharing technique that we
learned in the last several sections.
However, the secret sharing technique that we used was only working with integers,
but federated learning gradients tend to be decimal numbers.
So we want to be able to convert our decimal numbers into an integer format,
so that we can actually aggregate them using a secret sharing technique.
For that, we're going to look at what's called a
fixed precision encoding and it's really quite a simple technique,
and we're going to go through a little bit of it here.
We're not going to dive too deep into the theory in
a packet because this is really the thing that you want to lean on a toolkits.
You're going to lean on price if to really do this for you.
But, it's important to know how the information is being encoded under the hood.
Mostly, so that if you get undefined behavior,
maybe you set the precision to low
or you went to a tweet performance in one way or another.
You can just have a general idea of what this
this fixed precision encoding is really about.
So you'll be knowledgeable of what's going on under the hood.
So the first thing we're going to do is we want to
choose what precision we actually want to represent,
which means how many decimal points we actually want to encode our numbers with.
So we're going to take a decimal point like 0.5.
We're going to encode it as an integer.
We have to know how much storage we actually want to set
aside for information it's after the decimal point.
So for that, we need to set our base which we're going to use base 10 encoding,
which means that we're going to use
normal encoding if you wanted to think about it that way.
We could also use base two encoding which would be
binary and we're going to set up precision to be four.
So in this case, this is saying that we're going to
encode numbers of base 10 and then we're going
to have four decimal places that we're going to allow for storage,
and we also want to have a Q value and we're going to use
the same Q value we were using in the additive secret sharing technique,
and this is going to allow us to handle negative numbers as we'll see in a moment.
The first thing we want to do is we want to create
an encode function and this is going to
take our decimal number and convert it into an integer.
So we're going to return.
It does this using really simple technique.
It literally just takes our input decimal and
multiplies it times base to the power of precision.
So in this case, it just multiplies it by the number 10,000,
converts it to an integer,
and then takes the modulus, mod Q.
So if we want to encode the number 0.5,
we can now encode it as the number 5,000.
So 5,000 actually means 0.5.
We'll actually see that there are other kinds of ways that we do arithmetic.
They allow us to actually do decimal point operations while
everything is being stored in this integer type state.
Cool. So let's do a decode function.
Decode is literally just taking the same process in reverse.
I mean, it's quite simple.
So we'll say x fixed precision and
return x if x is less than equal to Q divided by two,
else x minus Q,
and here's the main part based to the power of precision.
So previously, the main parsing multiplied it by fixed precision.
Now, we're going to divide it by the size of our precision
and this is really just making it so that we can take into account negative numbers.
So if we encode a 0.5 as 5,000,
we can decode 5,000 as 0.5,
and so if I did negative.
So this ends up being a really large number.
It basically wraps around the other side of Q and we could decode this as negative 0.5.
So here we go.
This is how our fixed position encoding works.
A good example of addition.
If I were to add two numbers together,
so add 0.5 with 0.5.
So we say 5,000 plus 5,000,
decode 5,000 plus 5,000, decodes to one.
So some of these fall out naively,
multiplication, other operations can get more tricky, but again,
it's not something I want you to worry about too much
because you really going to lean on top of
a toolkit to handle fixed precision encoding for you.
In the same way, you lean on your processor right now to
do most of the low-level arithmetic for you.
It's just good to have an idea for this is happening under the hood to enable you to be
able to use the secret sharing techniques that actually
converting all your numbers into these fixed precision format.
In this particular case, if the precision is set to something like four,
it also means you're losing a few decimal places worth of value.
So if originally were using a 32-bit encoding.
Anyway, this big decimal value which is our gradient,
we're going to lose the end of that.
If we're using a precision that only allocates four decimal places of precision.
We can make this larger or smaller.
It will affect performance and memory and things like that.
That's just a good thing to understand and take into
account when you're adjusting your fixed precision encoding.
All right, and with that let's move on to the next section.