In the final project for this course,
I'd like for you to build on the first project where you
perform federated learning with a trusted secure aggregator.
In this project, I'd like for you to take
the same neural networks you worked with in the first project,
and aggregate gradients using additive secret sharing and
fixed precision encoding as you learn about in the last several lessons.
Make sure you use at least the three data owners per aggregation.
This will ensure that no one will ever see anyone's gradients other than their own,
protecting the privacy without needing to trust a secure aggregator.
Okay. So in this next project,
what I would like for you to do is leverage
this secret sharing technique that you learned about in the last section,
right using PySyft where you can do a fixed precision of
encoding of an additive secret sharing tensor,
and I want you to actually use this to
aggregate gradients in the federated learning contexts, right?
So take the same example that we were working with
towards the beginning of this lesson where we were using
a trusted third party to form the aggregation and just
replace the trusted third party with this encryption protocol,
with this additive secret sharing protocol,
so that no one actually has to share their own gradients with any other worker directly,
instead they will encrypt it, right?
Encrypt the individual values so that you the data scientist can actually pull up
the model and average the gradients from
these multiple different workers without
anyone ever seeing a gradient that isn't their own.
So I wish you the best of luck with this project,
and I'll see you in the next section.