In the last project, we created a function which lets us
generate every parallel database to a given input database.
In this concept, we're going to learn how to query this database,
and then measure the privacy of that query.
How are we going to do this?
Well, we're going to compare the output of the query on the entire database,
with the output of the query on each of the parallel databases.
In this way, we're going to see how the query
changes when we remove an individual from the database.
Let's unpack this a bit.
So intuitively, we want to query our database and
evaluate whether the result of our query is leaking private information.
As I mentioned, this is about evaluating whether the output of
the query changes when you remove someone from the database.
Specifically, we want to evaluate
the maximum amount that the query changes when someone is removed,
maximum over all possible people who could be removed.
So in order to evaluate how much privacy is leaked,
we're going to iterate over each person in the database and measure the difference
in the output of the query relative to when we would query the entire database.
In this section, I'm going to show you how to create
a function or a query over a database and then
empirically evaluate the sensitivity of
that function to two people being removed from the database that we're querying.
So we're going to query the full database and then we're
going to look at querying every possible parallel databases.
We're going to look at the output of these queries and say,
what's the maximum amount that they differ?
Now, entity thing to remember as I am doing this is that the in
production we won't necessarily use
this technique to actually measure the sensitivity of that function.
As we'll find it a minute, it turns out that
different functions actually have a pretty consistent sensitivity,
which we can know a priori.
But before we jump to that,
let's start with a simple query.
I think that the simplest possible query we can have on the database is a simple sum.
So first let's create a database,
so let's create a database at 20 entries.
Then we have every parallel database.
This database sends to the function that we created in the last screencast.
Okay. So what we want to do,
is we want to then define a function which queries as database,
and the one that we want to do first,
I think it's sort of the simplest and most intuitive is a simple sum.
So let's create a function called query,
pass the database and return the sum of that database.
So query db.
Looks like there are 10 ones in this database, right?
So if we recreate it again,
looks like sometimes there's 13,
obviously this is randomly generated database,
the number of ones in the output of this query tends to change.
However, if we look at this database, it's 13,
and then we query parallel database one,
that was only 12.
For a lot this is only 12.
So as you can see, when we remove people from this database,
it changes the output of the query.
What does this mean? What this means is that the output of this query is actually
conditioned directly on information from a lot of people in this database.
So as it turns out,
if this wasn't true, right?
If the sensitivity was say zero,
then that would mean that we get the same output
of the query regardless of who we remove from the database.
So obviously this is not the case for some,
but they could be functions later which do have zero sensitivity.
Let's actually look and see what is the maximum amount that
this query changes when we remove someone from the database.
So we iterate over every single person in the database,
all these parallel databases,
and just compute the query for them,
and then see what's the maximum math they change from this query over the full database.
All right. So let's call this the full result, right?
So the full query, or full DB.
Now, let's iterate over every parallel database.
So for PDB in PDBs,
as you recall, this is a list of databases.
Then we're going to compute a parallel database result equals query PDB.
Then we want to evaluate the distance,
so I will say the max distance is originally zero.
Then we want to make a comparison between this PDB result and the full DB result.
We actually don't care about the sign here.
We're just looking for the absolute distance, right?
As you might remember from the previous,
I mentioned this was called the L1 sensitivity.
This is because we're computing this sum directly.
If we were to square this, it will become the L2 just like sort of L1 and L2 norms.
Let's just put this DB distance equals this.
Then if DB distance is greater than max distance,
max distance equals DB distance.
So let's see what are our max distances.
Our max distance is one.
Now, let's think about this for a second.
Why is our max distance one?
Let's actually make this database a lot bigger, and so we just do it,
we'll say with 5,000 people,
right and see what our max distance says.
Look, as you can see, our max distance is still one.
What does it turn out? Our database is binary database, right?
So all of these entries in the database are either one or zero,
which means that if we're computing a sum over it,
the maximum amount that the output of a query could change is just by one,
because you're removing a person from this database.
This teaches us something, right?
So some actually has a consistent sensitivity.
So even though we're calculating it
empirically or actually we're iterating through the data,
and seeing how much it changes,
this is actually an unnecessary step,
like we don't have to do this because we know something
about our database and then we know something
about the function that we're computing our database.
We know that the maximum value of any value in a database is a one,
and the minimum value is a zero.
So that the most that anyone could change as
some query is one minus zero which is one, right?
So this is max distance.
So intuitively just for the purpose of teaching sensitivity,
we're walking through this sort of explicit calculation,
and we'll continue to do this just like a teaching tool.
In real world production use cases,
this would be inefficient and sometimes
inaccurate if you happen to have a database that had all zeros in it for example.
When you actually do this in the real world,
the a priori knowledge that you know about your database like
the maximum and minimum values in the query that you're computing,
is actually sufficient to know the sensitivity.
So let's go ahead and rename this.
We could probably rename this empirical sensitivity,
so I'm just calling it sensitivity but for the sake of just
teaching these techniques and getting
an intuitive feeling for what sensitive is all about.
I think that this is going to be sufficient.
Now this definition, the maximum amount that
the query changes when removing an individual from the database,
has a specific term.
It's called the L1 sensitivity or simply the sensitivity for short.
This is going to be an incredibly important measure because it
allows us to understand an aspect of a certain kind of query.
It's actually going to ground our later analysis
comparing how different queries do or do not leak information.
In this particular case,
a sum actually leaks quite a bit of information.
The output of the sum is conditioned on
every single individual that has a one in there rho of the database.
In the next section, we're going to write some more code to check
the sensitivity of any function generically.