What I'd like for you to do in the next project is consolidate the code that I
showed you in the last concept into a single function called sensitivity.
It should accept a function,
the query, as input,
as well as the number of entries that you want to run this database over.
This function should then initialize a database of the appropriate size,
initialize all of the parallel databases,
run the query over the entire database,
and all parallel databases and correctly calculate the sensitivity of the function,
which as you may remember is the maximum distance between
the full database query output and any parallel database.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next concept.