In this section, we're going to take the code that we use to generate
an empirical sensitivity measure in the last green test and
we're going to roll it up together into a function called sensitivity,
which can take any query and empirically
measure how sensitive it is to removing people from a database.
The first thing we want to do is we want to copy the code that we created before.
So this is what generated a database
and created every parallel database to that database.
Then, we're going to copy some query.
We can do copy the line actually queries,
this database, and then how we calculated sensitivity.
So we're going to change this back to max_distance.
Perfect. What we want do here is
really just consolidate this code into a single function which accepts
this query function as
an input parameter and then returned to sensitivity of this function.
As mentioned last time, this is empirically measuring sensitivity.
The idea here is just to get a sense intuition for,
if we were to actually remove you from a database,
how much would the query change?
But in the real world, we can typically know about sensitivity through other ways.
So let's do this def sensitivity and we're going to accept two parameters.
One is going to be the query,
which is a function object and then the next is going to be
the number of entries in the database that we want to query with.
So here we replace this 5,000 with this in entries variable.
Then, we're going to query the database that we created,
calculate the maximum distance from the full database query and every parallel database,
and return this max_distance.
Let's calculate sensitivity of this sum function.
As we saw before in the previous video,
the sensitivity is one.
Now, let's change this function.
Let's cast it to a float and let's calculate a mean.
So as you know mean it's just a sum divided by the number of entries.
So we should expect that whereas previously
our sensitivity is one because we are dividing this by a large number,
this should decrease sensitivity quite significantly.
As we see here, it truly does.
So the sensitivity empirical sensitivity here is 0.0005
and this corresponds to the average value in the database.
So this is typically returning something like 500 or something near 500.
So the average value here would be 0.5 divided by the number of entries.
This is what's giving us this notion.
Since this database is randomly generated,
if we ran into sensitivity a bunch of times,
we'd actually get numbers just above and just below.
It would approximate the true sensitivity which is really what
this sampling does but as it happens here,
it tend to line up with the exact sensitivity of this function.
This is pretty great. So the nice thing about this convenient function here is that
we can pass in arbitrary functions.
We can empirically get a sense for how much the output of
this function changes when we remove a person from a database.
Now, I want to go ahead and discuss and really
dive a little bit deeper into this last assumption here,
in these databases that we're creating.
So let's go ahead and just pull out here so we can see database.
Let's create one of size 20.
In this database, every single one of these values
corresponds to a different person or we're sort of assuming this.
So when I'm removing someone from the database,
when I'm calculating every parallel database,
my assumption is that none of these are
accidentally referring to the same person because the the notion of
sensitivity is not about how much
the function changes when we remove a value from the database,
it's about how much a function changes when we remove
all values corresponding to a person from the database.
We care about the sensitivity to people,
not necessarily the sensitivity just to individual values.
Now, it so happens that that's the same thing in the databases they're using right now,
but I really wanted to call out this notion just so that
you get a feeling for what we're really trying to calculate here.
What we're really trying to calculate is how much the output value from this function
is using information from each individual person database,
or is it only an aggregation of
the information that actually multiple people are contributing?
We'll find that it's a lot easier to protect privacy,
if the information that's being returned from our query,
the output of this function is actually
information that multiple people are contributing to.
So we might say intuitive measure here might be a threshold
or various other functions which have a much smaller sensitivity profile.
In the next few sections, we're going to
explore functions like this. So I'll see you there.