Okay. So in project three,
I'd like for you to play around with this notion of sensitivity yourself.
Specifically, I'd like for you to calculate
the sensitivity for this new function, which is the threshold function.
This project is going to take three steps.
First, create the query function, where you compute the sum over
the database and return whether that sum is
greater than or less than a certain threshold.
Then, I want you to create 10 databases of
size 10 and query them with a threshold of five,
calculating the sensitivity of each.
Finally, I want you to print out the sensitivity of
all 10 databases so you can see them compared to each other.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next concept.