In this video, we're going to calculate the sensitivity for a new kind of function,
and that function is the threshold function.
We're first going to define a new query,
which is computing this threshold function,
then we're going to create 10 databases of size 10 and compute
this function over them with a threshold of five and calculate the sensitivity each time.
So, step number one is to create this new query type.
So, let's say def query like we did before,
which passes in a database,
and then it returns the sum over the database and whether or
not that is greater than a certain threshold,
which we'll set the default to be five.
Now, I know the priority that this actually returns a binary value,
because it's either greater than or less than.
So, we want to go ahead and cast it to a float because this is our sensitivity function,
it's actually equipped to use.
The interesting thing here is that we run this query on data database.
So, let's say, let's grab a database iteration function up here.
Let's create 10.
So, if we look at database and we just compute a sum over it, notice these changes.
There is some deviation,
so sometimes it's going to be greater than
a threshold and sometimes it's going to be less than threshold.
So, if we actually query the database, we see this.
So, sometimes it's one, sometimes it's
zero and the other interesting thing I want you to consider.
So, let's go ahead and go at db.sum,
and let's look for one that's six.
Okay. So, this database,
this should return true.
So, we have db.sum greater than five,
returns one or returns true.
So, when it returns one, it's returning a true,
and when it turns zero, it's actually returning a false.
So, when we're querying the database, we get one.
Now, the interesting thing here is that this
means that there are going to be a parallel databases that could be a five.
So, this is the nature of how the output of this query
can change if we remove an individual from the dataset,
because if we remove someone,
it could cause this sum to go from
six to five and thus the threshold to go from true to false.
However, if we have a database with only four people in it for example,
well then the query is false, right?
But no matter who we remove,
this query is going to continue to be false because removing someone from the dataset
only makes the output of the query smaller.
So, this means that for some databases,
we would have positive sensitivity and for other databases it seems almost as if
we would have no sensitivity because
no matter how many people we removed or who we removed,
the output of this threshold query is no different.
So, the way we're going check this out,
is to explicitly compute the sensitivity.
So, sens_f equals sensitivity of
the query and number of entries equals five. There we go.
So, now let's do this 10 times and print out the sensitivity of each.
So, my theory actually isn't holding up.
It looks as though our sensitivity is always zero.
This is very surprising and this to me actually seems
like it could be a bug of some sort,
no, entries should be 10.
Okay. So, we have databases size 10.
Sometimes the sum is greater than one,
sometimes it's greater than five,
sometimes the sum is less than five.
However, the sensitivity itself changes and what these actually correspond to,
is a non-zero sensitivity is when the sum of the database is exactly six.
Because of the sum of the databases is exactly six,
then it's sitting right above the threshold,
and so when we remove someone,
it can actually drop down to five thus
causing the output of the query to be different and the sensitivity to be one.
But the rest of the time,
when the sum of the database is not six.
So, it's significantly below or significantly above six,
then [inaudible] of the database doesn't change the output of the query.
Now, what does this mean?
In previous examples, we've seen a constant sensitivity.
We saw some function over binary always has a sensitivity of one,
and when our mean had a very consistent sensitivity as well,
but this has a variable sensitivity.
Now, remember previously I discussed in the previous sections,
we talked about how we wouldn't actually use this empirical sensitivity in practice,
because it's very inefficient right and sometimes it's not actually perfectly accurate.
So, in a context of say, a sum function,
we can simply know that the maximum sensitivity of a sum over a database is
the maximum value or maximum range of
values that any one of those items that you could remove would take on.
So, in this particular case,
however this seems to be different because the sensitivity
here is somewhat dataset specific.
So, theoretically, the maximum sensitivity of a threshold is always one as well.
Because the maximum amount that they were moving someone
from a function including a threshold is one.
That's the most that it can change,
you can either go from a one to a zero.
However, if we actually take a peek at the data,
we can tell that sometimes it's going to be one and sometimes it's not going to be one.
Now, when implementing differential privacy for the first time,
this is how you want to compute sensitivity.
Like on the [inaudible] you want to compute it theoretically.
You want to say that, "Hey, I'm doing a threshold that means with sensitivity is one,
and that's what I'm going to use."
However, there are some more advanced techniques
one of which we'll look later that actually allows you
to kind of take a peek at the data and try to
understand what's called a data conditioned sensitivity.
The classic simpler use case that we're going to learn
about first is not data conditional sensitivity.
So, sensitivity just based on the function and what we
know about the potential range of the data.
But data conditioned sensitivity is
sensitivity calculated not just based on the range that we know the data can take,
but actually the values in the database.
So, this is a database conditioned sensitivity query.
So, for now when you're working with differential privacy,
still focus on just the pure theoretical calculation
of the sensitivity for any given function.
Just consider in your mind what
the maximum sensitivity that function could be and eventually,
we'll get to some of these more advanced concepts that allow
you to actually look inside at the dataset values.
I hope it has been educational for you and I'll see you in the next section.