In this concept, we're going to explore how to compromise or attack differential privacy.
In particular, we want to talk about
the simplest attack, which is called a differencing attack.
Sadly, none of the functions we've looked at so far are differentially private,
despite them having varying levels of sensitivity.
We're going to demonstrate this here by using this differencing attack.
So let's say we want to figure out a specific person's value in the database.
If we're able to perform a query using a sum,
all we would have to do is query for the sum of
the entire database and then the sum of the entire database without that person.
In SQL, this might look something like this.
As you can see, by comparing these two SQL queries,
we can determine whether John Doe actually had cancer.
So what I'd like for you to do in the next project is
perform this differencing attack using the sum,
mean, and threshold query functions we already created.
The purpose of this exercise is to give you an intuition for
how privacy can fail in these environments.