In this project, we want to perform
a basic differencing attack to divulge what the value is in database,
specifically the value on row 10.
The way we're going to do this, we're going to perform
two different queries against the database.
One, which is a query that includes row 10 and then we're going to
perform a query against the database excluding row 10.
The idea is we want be able to compare
these two different queries and determine what the exact value of row 10 actually is.
So the first we want to do is initialize a database,
we'll put a 100 values in it.
Then we want to initialize a parallel database,
meaning a database with just row 10 missing.
So this is the same as doing a SQL query,
where it select some function
where database value does not equal and then the index of a specific number, right?
So if for example in this database,
if every person was associated with Bob, now we're saying, okay.
Run this query, where name does not equal Bob, right?
That's what this is going to be. This is the whole database,
it's the database with one person missing.
So parallel database would be,
get parallel database from the database where we're going to remove index 10.
Cool? All right.
So let's see what's actually- what's the true thing we're trying to divulge.
So there's a one here, right?
But we're going to try to learn,
there's a one here by virtue the fact
that we're doing multiple queries against these two databases.
So the simplest form we can do is just a sum.
So the sum of the database minus sum of the parallel database,
this will divulge the exact value, right?
So as you can see, it equals one.
If this equals zero, this would equal zero we could try that in a second.
So this is differencing attack using addition, using a sum query.
We can do the same thing with
a mean query but all we do is just divide by laying of length the DB.
Technically, other operations means we don't have to do this.
Got to cast a float.
Cool. So as you can see it's non-zero,
so we know that this is indeed a one because the database of ones and zeros.
Then of course, we can do a differencing attack using a threshold query.
So for this one,
you can base it off this one I
think and really what we're going to do is we're going to say,
is this greater than,
what was the actual sum?
50, so this is 49, sorry.
So this will return true because the sum over the database is
actually equal to 50 so it should be true but this one will be false, right?
So we actually adjust it within 49.
All right. So this will return true, this one will turn false and
the difference between the two will be one.
So as you can see using these three different attacks,
they're all doing the same thing, right?
They're performing a query with a value that's missing.
As you should be familiar with this point,
given the intuitions around difference or privacy that we've been formulating,
this differencing attack is very close to the heart
of the intuitions behind differential privacy.
So as we form differential private techniques,
we want them to specifically be immune to these kinds of attacks.
As we'll see in a formal definition of differential privacy, this is very,
very close to the- there's a constraint that we must satisfying or
satisfy differential privacy to a certain threshold. See you in the next lesson.